[
    {
        "Answer": "Surah e Al-Imran",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah e Al-baqarah",
        "Choice2": "Surah e Hajj",
        "Choice3": "Surah e Al-Imran",
        "Choice4": "Surah e Fatah",
        "Question": "_____ is the Surah in Holy Quran in which Hajj is commanded:",
        "id": 0
    },
    {
        "Answer": "86",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "87",
        "Choice2": "77",
        "Choice3": "86",
        "Choice4": "76",
        "Question": "There are ____ Makki Surahs in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 1
    },
    {
        "Answer": "28",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "28",
        "Choice2": "38",
        "Choice3": " 48",
        "Choice4": " 18",
        "Question": "There are ____ Madni Surahs in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 2
    },
    {
        "Answer": "558",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "548",
        "Choice2": "558",
        "Choice3": "568",
        "Choice4": "578",
        "Question": "There are ____ Rukus in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 3
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah-e-Al Baqarah",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah-e-Al Imran",
        "Choice2": " Surah-e- Maryam",
        "Choice3": "Surah-e-Yousuf",
        "Choice4": "Surah-e-Al Baqarah",
        "Question": "The longest Surah in Holy Quran is:",
        "id": 4
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Al- Kausar ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah e Ahad",
        "Choice2": " Surah e Nasr",
        "Choice3": "Al- Kausar",
        "Choice4": "Surah e Lahab",
        "Question": "_____ is the shortest Surah in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 5
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah e An Naas ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah e Ahad",
        "Choice2": "Surah e Nasr",
        "Choice3": "Surah e An Naas",
        "Choice4": "Surah e Lahab",
        "Question": "The last Surah of Holy Quran is:",
        "id": 6
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Al-Faitha",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": " Al-Baqarah",
        "Choice2": " Al-Faitha",
        "Choice3": "Surah e yaseen",
        "Choice4": "Surah e Lahab",
        "Question": "  ___ is the preface of the Holy Quran.",
        "id": 7
    },
    {
        "Answer": "5",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "5",
        "Choice2": "7",
        "Choice3": " 9",
        "Choice4": "3",
        "Question": "______  verses were reveled in the first wahi: ",
        "id": 8
    },
    {
        "Answer": "700 ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "500",
        "Choice2": "300",
        "Choice3": "700",
        "Choice4": "900",
        "Question": "Namaz commanded in Holy Quran for:",
        "id": 9
    },
    {
        "Answer": "6666",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "7777",
        "Choice2": "8888",
        "Choice3": "6666",
        "Choice4": "5555",
        "Question": " The number of Ayats in Holy Quran are: ",
        "id": 10
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Usman Ghani (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakar (R.A)",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat Umer (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Zaid (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Usman Ghani (R.A)",
        "Question": " Who was the first Hafiz Quran among Sahaba:",
        "id": 11
    },
    {
        "Answer": "6",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "4",
        "Choice2": "6",
        "Choice3": "8",
        "Choice4": "10",
        "Question": " Gap between first wahy and second wahy was _____ months:",
        "id": 12
    },
    {
        "Answer": "12",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "10",
        "Choice2": "12",
        "Choice3": "14",
        "Choice4": "16",
        "Question": "______ Ghazawahs described in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 13
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Al Saf  ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Al Saf",
        "Choice2": "Muhammad",
        "Choice3": "Zuha",
        "Choice4": "Surah Al Teen",
        "Question": "Holy Prophet Hazrat Muhammad ﷺ  is addressed as Ahmed in Surah:",
        "id": 14
    },
    {
        "Answer": "5",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "3",
        "Choice2": "6",
        "Choice3": "4",
        "Choice4": "5",
        "Question": "How many Surah in Holy Quran started with the word Qul:",
        "id": 15
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Umer (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": " Hazrat Abu Bakar (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Umer (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Zaid (R.A)",
        "Choice4": " Hazrat Usman Ghani (R.A)",
        "Question": " Who  proposed the compilation of Holy Quran:",
        "id": 16
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Surah e Al Nasr ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah e Fatah",
        "Choice2": "Surah e Al Nasr",
        "Choice3": "Surah e Al Naas",
        "Choice4": "None Of These",
        "Question": " Which Surah in Holy Quran is known as Surah Widah?",
        "id": 17
    },
    {
        "Answer": "6 ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "5",
        "Choice2": "3",
        "Choice3": "6",
        "Choice4": "7",
        "Question": "The word Islam Occurs _____ times in Holy Quran is:",
        "id": 18
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Abdul Malik Marwan",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": " Hujaj Bin Yousuf",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Umar",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Usman",
        "Choice4": "Abdul Malik Marwan",
        "Question": "______________ applied the dots in the Holy Quran?",
        "id": 19
    },
    {
        "Answer": "8",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "8",
        "Choice2": "6",
        "Choice3": "4",
        "Choice4": "10",
        "Question": "How many Sapara in Holy Quran starts with bismillah?",
        "id": 20
    },
    {
        "Answer": "3",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "3",
        "Choice2": "4",
        "Choice3": "5",
        "Choice4": "6",
        "Question": " _____ Surah starts with “Ya Ayananabiyau” in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 21
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah Yaseen",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Suran Zuha",
        "Choice2": "Surah Fatiah",
        "Choice3": "Surah Rehman",
        "Choice4": "Surah Yaseen",
        "Question": " Which Surah in Holy Quran is known as Heart of Quran?",
        "id": 22
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah Rehman",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Suran Zuha",
        "Choice2": "Surah Fatiah",
        "Choice3": "Surah Rehman",
        "Choice4": "Surah Yaseen",
        "Question": " Which Surah in Holy Quran is known as  beauty of Quran?",
        "id": 23
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah e Alaq",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah e Alaq",
        "Choice2": "Surah e Rehman",
        "Choice3": "Surah e Fatiah",
        "Choice4": "Surah e Al Teen",
        "Question": " First revealed surah was:",
        "id": 24
    },
    {
        "Answer": "26",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "25",
        "Choice2": "26",
        "Choice3": "27",
        "Choice4": "28",
        "Question": "How many Prophets mentioned in holy Quran?",
        "id": 25
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Surah Al Baqarah",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": " Surah Al Baqarah",
        "Choice2": "Surah Al Imran",
        "Choice3": "Surah Al Yousuf",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Longest Ayat of Holy Quran is in:",
        "id": 26
    },
    {
        "Answer": "6",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "4",
        "Choice2": "5",
        "Choice3": "6",
        "Choice4": " 7",
        "Question": "How many Surah start with the name of Prophets (A.S) in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 27
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Women  ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Men",
        "Choice2": "Women",
        "Choice3": "Widow",
        "Choice4": "None of These",
        "Question": "Surah Maryam wholly revealed for a:",
        "id": 28
    },
    {
        "Answer": "22 years and 5 months",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "18 years and 10 months",
        "Choice2": "23 years and 5 months",
        "Choice3": "22 years and 5 months",
        "Choice4": " 21 years and 5 months",
        "Question": "Holy Quran was reveled in how many years and months?",
        "id": 29
    },
    {
        "Answer": " 7",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "8",
        "Choice2": "7",
        "Choice3": "6",
        "Choice4": "5",
        "Question": "There are _____ stages in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 30
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah-e-Al Imran",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah-e-Al Imran",
        "Choice2": " Surah-e- Maryam",
        "Choice3": "Surah-e-Yousuf",
        "Choice4": " Surah-e-Al Baqarah",
        "Question": "Second longest Surah in Holy Quran is:",
        "id": 31
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah-e-Al Baqarah",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah-e-Al Imran",
        "Choice2": "Surah-e- Maryam",
        "Choice3": "Surah-e-Yousuf",
        "Choice4": " Surah-e-Al Baqarah",
        "Question": "The longest Surah in Holy Quran is:",
        "id": 32
    },
    {
        "Answer": "2",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "3",
        "Choice2": "2",
        "Choice3": " 1",
        "Choice4": "None Of These",
        "Question": "How many number of stones mentioned in Holy Quran?",
        "id": 33
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Surah e namal",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Surah e namal",
        "Choice2": "Surah e Nasr",
        "Choice3": "Surah e An Naas",
        "Choice4": "Surah e Lahab",
        "Question": "In which Surah of Holy Quran Ant is mentioned:",
        "id": 34
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Spider",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Ant",
        "Choice2": "Pigeon",
        "Choice3": "Spider",
        "Choice4": "None Of These",
        "Question": "Surah e Ankaboot in Holy Quran Means:",
        "id": 35
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "5",
        "Choice2": "4",
        "Choice3": "6",
        "Choice4": "3",
        "Question": "How many times name of Muhammad mentioned in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 36
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Zaid Bin Haris(R.A) ",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakar (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Umer (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Zaid Bin Haris(R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Usman Ghani (R.A)",
        "Question": "Only Sahabi  mentioned in Holy Quran is:",
        "id": 37
    },
    {
        "Answer": "92",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "92",
        "Choice2": "82",
        "Choice3": "72",
        "Choice4": "62",
        "Question": "The word islam  has been used at _____ places in Holy Quran:",
        "id": 38
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Saff",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Ya-Seen",
        "Choice2": "Muhammad",
        "Choice3": "Saff",
        "Choice4": "Muzzammil",
        "Question": "Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) is called with the name “Ahmed” in Surah",
        "id": 39
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Fath",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Ya-Seen",
        "Choice2": "Muhammad",
        "Choice3": "Muzzammil",
        "Choice4": "Fath",
        "Question": "“Muhammad is the messenger of Allah” is stated in Surah",
        "id": 40
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Ahzaab",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Aal-e-Imraan",
        "Choice2": "Yaaseen",
        "Choice3": " Muhammad",
        "Choice4": " Ahzaab",
        "Question": "Allah says, “Wives of Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) are mothers of believers” in Surah",
        "id": 41
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "1",
        "Choice2": "2",
        "Choice3": " 3",
        "Choice4": "4",
        "Question": "The name “Muhammad” has been mentioned _________ times in the Holy Quran.",
        "id": 42
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Al-Namal",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Aal-e-Imraan",
        "Choice2": "Al-Namal",
        "Choice3": "Yaaseen",
        "Choice4": "Muhammad",
        "Question": "Which Surah of Quran has Bismillah twice?.",
        "id": 43
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Al-Toba",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": " Al-Baqara",
        "Choice2": "Al-Nisa",
        "Choice3": "Al-Toba",
        "Choice4": "Al-Ikhlas",
        "Question": "Which surah starts without “Bismillah” ?",
        "id": 44
    },
    {
        "Answer": "114",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "124",
        "Choice2": " 109",
        "Choice3": "114",
        "Choice4": "220",
        "Question": "How many surah does the Holy Quran contain?",
        "id": 45
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Al-Maidah",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Al-Maidah",
        "Choice2": "Al-Baqara",
        "Choice3": "Al-Mominoon",
        "Choice4": " Al-Nisa",
        "Question": "Which surah contains the orders about Wuzu, Ghusal and Tayammum?",
        "id": 46
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ghazwah Ohad",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Ghazwah Ohad",
        "Choice2": " Ghazwah Badar",
        "Choice3": "Ghazwah Khaibar",
        "Choice4": "Ghazwah Khandaq",
        "Question": "Which famous Ghazwah is mentioned in surah Al-Imran?",
        "id": 47
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Dog",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Dog",
        "Choice2": "Cat",
        "Choice3": "Horse",
        "Choice4": "Woodpecker",
        "Question": "In surah kahf, which animal is mentioned along with the Ashaab-e-Kahf?",
        "id": 48
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Human",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "Universe",
        "Choice2": "Earth",
        "Choice3": "Animal",
        "Choice4": "Human",
        "Question": "Subject of Holy Quran is ?",
        "id": 49
    },
    {
        "Answer": "30",
        "Categ": "Quran Majeed",
        "Choice1": "30",
        "Choice2": "20",
        "Choice3": "25",
        "Choice4": "None Of These",
        "Question": " Al-Quran is divided into how many parts?",
        "id": 50
    },
    {
        "Answer": " 571 A.D ",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " 571 A.D ",
        "Choice2": " 561 A.D ",
        "Choice3": " 551 A.D ",
        "Choice4": " 575 A.D ",
        "Question": "Holy Prophet Hazrat Muhammad ﷺ was born in :",
        "id": 51
    },
    {
        "Answer": "3",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " 1",
        "Choice2": "2",
        "Choice3": "3",
        "Choice4": "4",
        "Question": "Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) had __________ sons.",
        "id": 52
    },
    {
        "Answer": "12",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "12",
        "Choice2": "15",
        "Choice3": "24",
        "Choice4": "35",
        "Question": "Hazrat Muhammad (SAW) went to syria with Abu-Talib at the age of",
        "id": 53
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Hazrat Halema (RA)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Hazrat Halema (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Sobia (RA)",
        "Choice3": " Hazrat Khola (RA)",
        "Choice4": "None Of These",
        "Question": "Name the foster mother(s) of the Holy Prophet (SAW)!",
        "id": 54
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Six months",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Two months",
        "Choice2": "Four months",
        "Choice3": "Six months",
        "Choice4": "One month",
        "Question": "How many months prior to the birth of Hazrat Muhammad (SAW), Hazrat Abdullah Ibn-e-Abdul Matalib died?",
        "id": 55
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Rabi-ul-Awal",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Jamadi-ul-Awwal",
        "Choice2": "Rabi-us-Sani",
        "Choice3": "Jamadi-us-Sani",
        "Choice4": "Rabi-ul-Awal",
        "Question": "The Holy prophet (SAW) was born in the month of",
        "id": 56
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Eight years",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Six years",
        "Choice2": "Eight years",
        "Choice3": "Ten years",
        "Choice4": "two years",
        "Question": "How many years after the birth of Holy Prophet (SAW), Hazrat Aamina died?",
        "id": 57
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Ismaeel (AS)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ismaeel (AS)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Eesaa (AS)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Da'ood (AS)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Saleh (AS)",
        "Question": "The Holy Prophet (SAW) was a direct descendent of ......",
        "id": 58
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Abu-Bakr (RA)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu-Bakr (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat usman (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Arqam (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Talha (RA)",
        "Question": "Name the person whose house became the center of preaching of Islam?",
        "id": 59
    },
    {
        "Answer": "615 AD",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "605 AD",
        "Choice2": "615 AD",
        "Choice3": "630 AD",
        "Choice4": "620 AD",
        "Question": "When did the second Migration to Habshah take place?",
        "id": 60
    },
    {
        "Answer": "7th year of Nabavi",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "8th year of Nabavi",
        "Choice2": "5th year of Nabavi",
        "Choice3": "6th year of Nabavi",
        "Choice4": "7th year of Nabavi",
        "Question": "When did the event of the social boycott of Banu Hashim take place?",
        "id": 61
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Hazrat Ibraheem (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ismaeel (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Ibraheem (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Moosa (A.S)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Eessaa (A.S)",
        "Question": " Hazrat Muhammad (PBUH) was born about three thousands years, after:",
        "id": 62
    },
    {
        "Answer": "25",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "25",
        "Choice2": "35",
        "Choice3": "20",
        "Choice4": "27",
        "Question": "At ____ age Holy Prophet (PBUH)  married to Hazrat Khadija ",
        "id": 63
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "1",
        "Choice2": "2",
        "Choice3": "3",
        "Choice4": "4",
        "Question": "Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) had __________daughters.",
        "id": 64
    },
    {
        "Answer": "6",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "4",
        "Choice2": "5",
        "Choice3": "6",
        "Choice4": "8",
        "Question": "For_____ years Haleema took care of Prophet",
        "id": 65
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Qaswa",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Buldul",
        "Choice2": "Anza",
        "Choice3": "Qaswa",
        "Choice4": "Zulifqar",
        "Question": "What is the name of the camel which the Holy Prophet (SAW) was riding in the migration of Madina?",
        "id": 66
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1st",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "1st",
        "Choice2": "2nd",
        "Choice3": "3rd",
        "Choice4": "4th",
        "Question": "Prophet was born in ___________ Year of Elephant.",
        "id": 67
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Banu Saad",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Banu Saad",
        "Choice2": " Banu Asad",
        "Choice3": "Banu Ummayya",
        "Choice4": "Banu Makhzoom",
        "Question": "In the beginning Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) worked as a shepherd for __________?",
        "id": 68
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khalid bin Waleed (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakr Siddique (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Umar Farooque (R.A)",
        "Choice3": " Ali Al-Murtaza (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Khalid bin Waleed (R.A)",
        "Question": "What companion of Prophet (PBUH) was awarded with the title of “The sword of Allah”?",
        "id": 69
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ali Al-Murtaza (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Umar Farooque (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Ali Al-Murtaza (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Hamza bin Abdul Mattalib (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Khalid bin Waleed (R.A)",
        "Question": "What companion of Prophet (PBUH) was awarded with the title of “The lion of Allah”?",
        "id": 70
    },
    {
        "Answer": "10",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "8",
        "Choice2": "9",
        "Choice3": "10",
        "Choice4": "11",
        "Question": "Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) lived in Madina for __________ years.",
        "id": 71
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Jibrael (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Jibrael (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Mikael (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Israfeel (A.S)",
        "Choice4": " Izraeel (A.S)",
        "Question": "The Angel who delivered messages to Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) from Allah was?",
        "id": 72
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "1",
        "Choice2": "2",
        "Choice3": "3",
        "Choice4": "4",
        "Question": "The name “Muhammad” has been mentioned _________ times in the Holy Quran.",
        "id": 73
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Zainab",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Ayesha",
        "Choice2": "Razia",
        "Choice3": " Zainab",
        "Choice4": " Fatima",
        "Question": "Lady named ___________ tried to poison the Holy Prophet ?",
        "id": 74
    },
    {
        "Answer": "surah Al-Fatha",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " surah Al-Fatha",
        "Choice2": "Surah Al-Kausar",
        "Choice3": "Surah Al-Anfal",
        "Choice4": "Surah Al-Ankaboot",
        "Question": "Prophet recited ____________ at the conquest of Makkah.",
        "id": 75
    },
    {
        "Answer": "15",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " 5",
        "Choice2": "10",
        "Choice3": "15",
        "Choice4": "20",
        "Question": "Prophet stayed at Makkah for __________ days after its conquest ?",
        "id": 76
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Abu Talha",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Umar",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Usman",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Abu Talha",
        "Question": "The grave of the Prophet was prepared by ?",
        "id": 77
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hafsa",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Ayesha",
        "Choice2": " Summaya",
        "Choice3": "Fatima",
        "Choice4": "Hafsa",
        "Question": "Daughter of Umer who married to Prophet was ?",
        "id": 78
    },
    {
        "Answer": "40 Years",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "38 Years",
        "Choice2": "39 Years",
        "Choice3": "40 Years",
        "Choice4": "41 Years",
        "Question": "At age of ___________ holy Prophet received first Wahi.",
        "id": 79
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Haleema",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Haleema",
        "Choice2": "Ruqya",
        "Choice3": "Summaya",
        "Choice4": " Bushra",
        "Question": "Hazrat ___________ was the foster mother of Holy Prophet.",
        "id": 80
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Holy Prophet Hazrat Muhammad (PBUH)",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Holy Prophet Hazrat Muhammad (PBUH)",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat Ibrahim (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Ismaeel (A.S)",
        "Choice4": " Hazrat Yaqoob (A.S)",
        "Question": "To which Prohpet Muslim Ummah Belongs?",
        "id": 81
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Miraj",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Miraj",
        "Choice2": " Hijrat",
        "Choice3": "Ghazwa Badar",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "On Which time the Holy Prohpet(PBUH) was gifted with Namaz?",
        "id": 82
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Sunnat",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": " Farz",
        "Choice2": " Wajib",
        "Choice3": " Nafl",
        "Choice4": " Sunnat",
        "Question": "The part of prayer the Holy Prophet ﷺ did is called_____________?",
        "id": 83
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Hira Cave",
        "Categ": "Hazrat Muhammad PBUH",
        "Choice1": "Sore Cave",
        "Choice2": " Hira Cave",
        "Choice3": "Khana-Kaaba",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "On which place, first Wahi was decended?",
        "id": 84
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Prophet Shoaib (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Prophet Dawood (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Prophet Nooh (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Prophet Yaqoob (A.S)",
        "Choice4": "Prophet Shoaib (A.S)",
        "Question": "Khateeb-ul-Ambia was the title of __________.",
        "id": 85
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ali Al-Murtaza (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakr Siddique (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Umar Farooq (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Usman Ghani (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Ali Al-Murtaza (R.A)",
        "Question": "Al-Hudaibiyah Treaty was scribed by __________.",
        "id": 86
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ameer Muawiyah (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Khalid bin Waleed (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Ameer Muawiyah (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Abu Ubaidah (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Amr bin Al-Aas (R.A)",
        "Question": "The first Ummayed Caliph was _________ ?",
        "id": 87
    },
    {
        "Answer": "578",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "578",
        "Choice2": " 579",
        "Choice3": "580",
        "Choice4": " 581",
        "Question": "Abdul Mutalib died in ___________ A.D.",
        "id": 88
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Umar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Ali",
        "Choice2": "Usman",
        "Choice3": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice4": " Umar",
        "Question": "Hazrat __________ proposed Azan for the first time ?",
        "id": 89
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Abu Talha",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": " Hazrat Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat Umar",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Usman",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Abu Talha",
        "Question": "The grave of the Prophet was prepared by ?",
        "id": 90
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Asad",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Ali",
        "Choice2": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice3": "Umar",
        "Choice4": "Asad",
        "Question": "Hazrat __________ died first among the Sahabah.",
        "id": 91
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Talha",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Qasim",
        "Choice2": "Saad",
        "Choice3": "Talha",
        "Choice4": "Asad",
        "Question": "Hazrat Usman Bin _________ was the Key holder of Kaaba.",
        "id": 92
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cloth",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Steel",
        "Choice2": "Cloth",
        "Choice3": "Coal",
        "Choice4": "Wheat",
        "Question": "Hazrat Abu Bakar was the merchant of ?",
        "id": 93
    },
    {
        "Answer": " 1st Muharram",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "1st Muharram",
        "Choice2": " 2nd Muharram",
        "Choice3": "3rd Muharram",
        "Choice4": "4th Muharram",
        "Question": "Hazrat Umar Farooq was martyred on ___________ 24 A.H.",
        "id": 94
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Umar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Usman",
        "Choice3": " Ali",
        "Choice4": "Umar",
        "Question": "Hazrat ____________ added As Salato Khairum Min Noum in Azan.",
        "id": 95
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Awais Karni",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": " Abdurreham",
        "Choice2": "Qasim",
        "Choice3": " Awais Karni",
        "Choice4": "Usman",
        "Question": "Only sahabi without seeing Prophet is ?",
        "id": 96
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Umar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Umar",
        "Choice2": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice3": "Usman",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Hazrat _____________ levied zakat on horses.",
        "id": 97
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ali",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": " Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Umar",
        "Choice3": "Usman",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Hazrat ________ lifted zakat on horses.",
        "id": 98
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Abu Bakar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Umar",
        "Choice2": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice3": "Usman",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Hazrat __________ had knowledge of dreams.",
        "id": 99
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Hazrat Usman (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakr (R.A)",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat Umar (R.A)",
        "Choice3": " Hazrat Usman (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Ali (R.A)",
        "Question": "Hazrat ___________ added 2nd Azan for Friday prayers.",
        "id": 100
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Abu Bakar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat Umar",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Usman",
        "Choice4": " Hazrat Ali",
        "Question": "Atique is the title of ?",
        "id": 101
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Umar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Umar",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Usman",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Ali",
        "Question": "Hazrat __________ established Department of Police.",
        "id": 102
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Usman",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Umar",
        "Choice3": "Usman",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Ghani was the title of Hazrat _________ (RA).",
        "id": 103
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ali",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Umar",
        "Choice3": "Usman",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Hazrat ____________ has the title the gateway to knowledge.",
        "id": 104
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ayub A.S",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Musa A.S",
        "Choice2": "Ayub A.S",
        "Choice3": "Haroon A.S",
        "Choice4": " Essa A.S",
        "Question": "For 18 years Hazrat _____________ suffered from skin disease.",
        "id": 105
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Zirr Ghaffari",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Abu Lahab",
        "Choice3": "Abu Jehl",
        "Choice4": "Zirr Ghaffari",
        "Question": "Hazrat ____________ is known as the first Dervish.",
        "id": 106
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Umar’s",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakar’s",
        "Choice2": "Umar’s",
        "Choice3": "Usman’s",
        "Choice4": " Ali’s",
        "Question": "First census of Islamic world in __________ period.",
        "id": 107
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Usman (R.A.)",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakar (R.A.)",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat  Umar (R.A.)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Usman (R.A.)",
        "Choice4": " Hazrat Ali (R.A.)",
        "Question": "Hazrat ____________ was the first Hafiz of the Holy Quran.",
        "id": 108
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Umar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice2": "Umar",
        "Choice3": "Usman",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Hazrat ___________ proposed the compilation of Holy Quran.",
        "id": 109
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khadija",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Amina",
        "Choice2": "Khadija",
        "Choice3": "Hafsa",
        "Choice4": "Ruqya",
        "Question": "Hazrat ___________ accepted Islam first in Women.",
        "id": 110
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Abu Bakar",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Usman",
        "Choice2": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice3": "Umar",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Hazrat ______________ accepted Islam first in Men.",
        "id": 111
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Usman (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Sahabee",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Abu Bakr (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Umar (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Usman (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Ali (R.A)",
        "Question": "who added 2nd Azan for friday prayers ?",
        "id": 112
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hafsah (R.A)",
        "Categ": "azwaj e mutahira",
        "Choice1": "Aisha (R.A)",
        "Choice2": " Juwairyyah (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Hafsah (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Maimoonah (R.A)",
        "Question": "Name the wife of Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) who was daughter of Umar Farooq (R.A)?",
        "id": 116
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Zainab (RA)",
        "Categ": "azwaj e mutahira",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ummay Habiba (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Ummay Salma (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Zainab (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Zainab Bint-t-Jahsh",
        "Question": "Name the wife of the Holy prophet (SAW) who was titled as Umm-ul-Masakeen?",
        "id": 117
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Siddiqa ",
        "Categ": "azwaj e mutahira",
        "Choice1": "Tahira",
        "Choice2": " Siddiqa ",
        "Choice3": "Umm-ul-Masakeen",
        "Choice4": "All of them",
        "Question": "What was the title of Hazrat Ayesha (RA)?",
        "id": 118
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Umm-e-Salma (RA)",
        "Categ": "azwaj e mutahira",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat safia (RA)",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat Ayesha (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Umm-e-Salma (RA)",
        "Choice4": " Hazrat Javeria( RA)",
        "Question": "Which Umm-ul-Momineen died last?",
        "id": 119
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Zainab bente Khuzima (RA)",
        "Categ": "azwaj e mutahira",
        "Choice1": "Harat Sauda (RA)",
        "Choice2": " Hazrat Zainab bente Jehash (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Zainab bente Khuzima (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Safia (RA)",
        "Question": "Umm-ul-Masakeen was the title given to one of the wives of the Prophet (SAW) ?",
        "id": 120
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Umal Mumneen Hafsah bint-e-Umar (R.A)",
        "Categ": "azwaj e mutahira",
        "Choice1": "Umal Mumneen Hazrat Aysha (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Umal Mumneen Hazrat Zainab (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Umal Mumneen Hafsah bint-e-Umar (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "Who was the First Women “Hafiz e Quran” to memorize the Holy Quran?",
        "id": 121
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazart Ayesha(RA)",
        "Categ": "azwaj e mutahira",
        "Choice1": "Hazart Fatma(RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazart Ayesha(RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazart Abu Bakar (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazart Umer(RA)",
        "Question": "Who was the first person who counted the Aayath (verses) of the Qur’an?",
        "id": 122
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Prophet Dawood (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Prophet Ibraheem (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Prophet Dawood (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Prophet Moosa (A.S)",
        "Choice4": "Prophet Essa (A.S)",
        "Question": "To what Prophet the Zabur was revealed by Allah?",
        "id": 123
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Prophet Essa (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Prophet Ibraheem (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Prophet Dawood (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Prophet Moosa (A.S)",
        "Choice4": " Prophet Essa (A.S)",
        "Question": "To what Prophet the Injeel was revealed by Allah?",
        "id": 124
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Muhammad bin Ismaeel",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Muhammad bin Ismaeel",
        "Choice2": "Muhammad Ismaeel",
        "Choice3": "Muhammad Ibraheem",
        "Choice4": "Ismaeel bin Ibraheem",
        "Question": "What was the name of Imam Bukhari (R.A)?",
        "id": 125
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Prophet Shoaib (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " Prophet Dawood (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Prophet Nooh (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Prophet Yaqoob (A.S)",
        "Choice4": "Prophet Shoaib (A.S)",
        "Question": "Khateeb-ul-Ambia was the title of __________.",
        "id": 126
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Lunar eclipse",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Lunar eclipse",
        "Choice2": "Solar eclipse",
        "Choice3": "earthquake",
        "Choice4": "heavy rain",
        "Question": "Namaz-e-Khasoof is offered at the time of __________ ?",
        "id": 127
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Izraeel (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Jibrael (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Mikael (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Israfeel (A.S)",
        "Choice4": "Izraeel (A.S)",
        "Question": "__________ takes out souls of life bearing creatures.",
        "id": 128
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jibrael (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " Jibrael (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Mikael (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Israfeel (A.S)",
        "Choice4": "Izraeel (A.S)",
        "Question": "Name the Angel who was appointed to deliver messages to Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) from Allah?",
        "id": 129
    },
    {
        "Answer": " An-Noor",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "As-Safa",
        "Choice2": "Sil",
        "Choice3": "Uhud",
        "Choice4": " An-Noor",
        "Question": "Cave Hira is in the _________ mountain.",
        "id": 130
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Masjid-ul-Haram",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Masjid-ul-Haram",
        "Choice2": " Masjid-e-Nabavi",
        "Choice3": "Masjid-e-Aqsa",
        "Choice4": "Masjid e Quba",
        "Question": "The first Msjid (Mosque) on the surface of Earth is?",
        "id": 131
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ali Al-Murtaza (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Abu Bakr Siddique (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Umar Farooq (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Usman Ghani (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Ali Al-Murtaza (R.A)",
        "Question": "Al-Hudaibiyah Treaty was scribed by __________.",
        "id": 132
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jibrael (A.S)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Jibrael (A.S)",
        "Choice2": "Mikael (A.S)",
        "Choice3": "Israfeel (A.S)",
        "Choice4": "Izraeel (A.S)",
        "Question": "The Angel who delivered messages to Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) from Allah was?",
        "id": 133
    },
    {
        "Answer": "40",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "36",
        "Choice2": "38",
        "Choice3": "40",
        "Choice4": "42",
        "Question": "Hazrat Ali (R.A) was martyred in __________ Hijrah?",
        "id": 134
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Palestine",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Saudi Arabia",
        "Choice2": " Syria",
        "Choice3": "Palestine",
        "Choice4": "Iraq",
        "Question": "Which country is called the “Land of Prophets”?",
        "id": 135
    },
    {
        "Answer": "6",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "5",
        "Choice2": "6",
        "Choice3": " 7",
        "Choice4": "8",
        "Question": "Siha e Sitta are __________ books of Hadith ?",
        "id": 136
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Wajib",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Wajib",
        "Choice2": "Farz",
        "Choice3": "Sunnat",
        "Choice4": "Mustahib",
        "Question": "Eid Prayer is __________ ?",
        "id": 137
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Imam Malik (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Imam Abu Haneefa (R.A)",
        "Choice2": " Imam Shafi (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Imam Ahmad bin Hambal (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Imam Malik (R.A)",
        "Question": "The book of Hadith, Al-Muwatta, was compiled by __________ ?",
        "id": 138
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Imam Abu Haneefa (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Imam Abu Haneefa (R.A)",
        "Choice2": "Imam Shafi (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Imam Ahmad bin Hambal (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Imam Malik (R.A)",
        "Question": "The book of Hadith, Kitaab-ul-Aathaar, was compiled by __________ ?",
        "id": 139
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Istilam",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Istilam",
        "Choice2": "Sayee",
        "Choice3": "Ramee",
        "Choice4": "Tawaf",
        "Question": "In Hajj, touching the Black Stone, is called__________ ?",
        "id": 140
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Abyssinia (Ethopia)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Makkah",
        "Choice2": "Madina",
        "Choice3": "Abyssinia (Ethopia)",
        "Choice4": "Baghdad",
        "Question": "The first migration of the Companions and relatives of the Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) was to __________ ?",
        "id": 141
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jews",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Muslims",
        "Choice2": "Christians",
        "Choice3": "Jews",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Banu Quraiza, Banu Nadir and Banu Qainuqa were three tribes of the_________?",
        "id": 142
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ahzaab",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " Aal-e-Imraan",
        "Choice2": "Yaaseen",
        "Choice3": "Muhammad",
        "Choice4": "Ahzaab",
        "Question": "Allah says, “Wives of Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) are mothers of believers” in Surah _________ .",
        "id": 143
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Al-Maidah",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Al-Maidah",
        "Choice2": "Al-Baqara",
        "Choice3": "Al-Mominoon",
        "Choice4": "Al-Nisa",
        "Question": "Which surah contains the orders about Wuzu, Ghusal and Tayammum ?",
        "id": 144
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ghazwah Ohad",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Ghazwah Ohad",
        "Choice2": "Ghazwah Badar",
        "Choice3": "Ghazwah Khaibar",
        "Choice4": "Ghazwah Khandaq",
        "Question": "Which famous Ghazwah is mentioned in surah Al-Imran ?",
        "id": 145
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Dog",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Dog",
        "Choice2": "Cat",
        "Choice3": "Horse",
        "Choice4": " woodpecker",
        "Question": "In surah kahf, which animal is mentioned along with the Ashaab e kahf ?",
        "id": 146
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Romans",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Romans",
        "Choice2": "Jews",
        "Choice3": "Iranis",
        "Choice4": "Christians",
        "Question": "The “Battle of Yermuk” was fought between Muslims and _________ ?",
        "id": 147
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Madina",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Makkah",
        "Choice2": "Madina",
        "Choice3": "Taif",
        "Choice4": "Palestine",
        "Question": "Masjid Qiblatain is in _________ ?",
        "id": 148
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ramee",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Istilam",
        "Choice2": "Sayee",
        "Choice3": "Ramee",
        "Choice4": "Tawaf",
        "Question": "In Hajj, stoning the Devil, is called __________ ?",
        "id": 149
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sayee",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Istilam",
        "Choice2": "Sayee",
        "Choice3": "Ramee",
        "Choice4": "Tawaf",
        "Question": "In Hajj, traveling seven times between Mount Safa and Mount Marwah, is called __________ ?",
        "id": 150
    },
    {
        "Answer": "7th",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "3rd",
        "Choice2": "4th",
        "Choice3": "6th",
        "Choice4": "7th",
        "Question": "Baitul Mamoor is on___________ Heaven?",
        "id": 151
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Zarar",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Quba",
        "Choice2": "Harmain",
        "Choice3": "Nabavi",
        "Choice4": "Zarar",
        "Question": "Mosque of ________ was demolished by prophet?",
        "id": 152
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ali",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Ali",
        "Choice2": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice3": "Umar",
        "Choice4": "Usman",
        "Question": "Hazrat ____________ conquered the fort of Qamus.",
        "id": 153
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Zainab",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Ayesha",
        "Choice2": "Razia",
        "Choice3": "Zainab",
        "Choice4": "Fatima",
        "Question": "Lady named ___________ tried to poison the Holy Prophet ?",
        "id": 154
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Nafeesa",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Fatima",
        "Choice2": "Kulsoom",
        "Choice3": "Nafeesa",
        "Choice4": "Sobia",
        "Question": "Friend of Khadija ____________ carried message of Nikah ?",
        "id": 155
    },
    {
        "Answer": "578",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "578",
        "Choice2": "579",
        "Choice3": "580",
        "Choice4": "581",
        "Question": "Abdul Mutalib died in ___________ A.D.",
        "id": 156
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Omar",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Abha",
        "Choice2": "Saleh",
        "Choice3": "Omar",
        "Choice4": "Ali",
        "Question": "Original name of Abu Jehl was ___________ bin Hisham.",
        "id": 157
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Abu jehl",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " Abu jehl",
        "Choice2": "Abu bakar",
        "Choice3": "Abu Lahab",
        "Choice4": "Abu Hurairah",
        "Question": "Abu-al-Hikm is the title of ?",
        "id": 158
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Iran",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Iraq",
        "Choice2": "Egypt",
        "Choice3": "Syria",
        "Choice4": "Iran",
        "Question": "King of __________ tore away the message of Prophet.",
        "id": 159
    },
    {
        "Answer": " 6",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " 5",
        "Choice2": " 6",
        "Choice3": "7",
        "Choice4": "8",
        "Question": "After __________ years of the birth of Holy prophet Bibi Amina died ?",
        "id": 160
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Rabiul Awal",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Muharram",
        "Choice2": "Shaaban",
        "Choice3": "Ramzan",
        "Choice4": " Rabiul Awal",
        "Question": "____________ was called month of migration ?",
        "id": 162
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1st",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "1st",
        "Choice2": "2nd",
        "Choice3": "3rd",
        "Choice4": " 4th",
        "Question": "Prophet addressed Khutba-e-Jumaa for first time in _________ Hijrah ?",
        "id": 163
    },
    {
        "Answer": "9th",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "8th",
        "Choice2": "9th",
        "Choice3": "10th",
        "Choice4": "11th",
        "Question": "Year of Deputation is ________________ Hijrah.",
        "id": 164
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1st",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "1st",
        "Choice2": "2nd",
        "Choice3": "3rd",
        "Choice4": "4th",
        "Question": "Moawakhat (the brotherhood) took place in __________ Hijrah ?",
        "id": 165
    },
    {
        "Answer": "2nd",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "1st",
        "Choice2": "2nd",
        "Choice3": "3rd",
        "Choice4": "4th",
        "Question": "Jehad was allowed in ______________ Hijrah ?",
        "id": 166
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cat",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Goat",
        "Choice2": "Ant",
        "Choice3": "Camel",
        "Choice4": "Cat",
        "Question": "Hurrirah means a ?",
        "id": 167
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1400",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "1300",
        "Choice2": "1400",
        "Choice3": "1500",
        "Choice4": "1600",
        "Question": "Companions of Prophet at Hudabiya were ?",
        "id": 168
    },
    {
        "Answer": "15",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "5",
        "Choice2": "10",
        "Choice3": " 15",
        "Choice4": "20",
        "Question": "Prophet stayed at Makkah for __________ days after its conquest ?",
        "id": 169
    },
    {
        "Answer": "619 A.D",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "618 A.D",
        "Choice2": "619 A.D",
        "Choice3": " 620 A.D",
        "Choice4": "621 A.D",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija and Hazrat Abu Talib died in ?",
        "id": 170
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Umar",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Ali",
        "Choice2": "Usman",
        "Choice3": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice4": "Umar",
        "Question": "Hazrat __________ proposed Azan for the first time ?",
        "id": 171
    },
    {
        "Answer": "313",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "313",
        "Choice2": "314",
        "Choice3": "315",
        "Choice4": "316",
        "Question": "_______ Muslims fought in the battle of Ghazwa-e-Badr ?",
        "id": 172
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "2",
        "Choice2": " 3",
        "Choice3": " 4",
        "Choice4": " 5",
        "Question": "_________ Kings accepted Islam when holy prophet sent them letters ?",
        "id": 173
    },
    {
        "Answer": "360",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "340",
        "Choice2": "350",
        "Choice3": "360",
        "Choice4": "370",
        "Question": "Idols in Kaba before Islam numbered ?",
        "id": 174
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hubal",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Hubal",
        "Choice2": "jabal",
        "Choice3": "Tabal",
        "Choice4": "Haleeb",
        "Question": "The largest idol named in kaaba was ?",
        "id": 175
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Nabvi",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Zarar",
        "Choice2": "Quba",
        "Choice3": "Hanafia",
        "Choice4": "Nabvi",
        "Question": "At Masjid-e-___________ first Muslim University was established ?",
        "id": 176
    },
    {
        "Answer": "yellow",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Black",
        "Choice2": "Red",
        "Choice3": "Green",
        "Choice4": "yellow",
        "Question": "The flag color of the Holy Prophet was white and __________ at the time of conquest of Makkah ?",
        "id": 177
    },
    {
        "Answer": "65",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "63",
        "Choice2": "64",
        "Choice3": "65",
        "Choice4": " 66",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija died at _______ years age?",
        "id": 178
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hafsa",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Ayesha",
        "Choice2": "Summaya",
        "Choice3": "Fatima",
        "Choice4": "Hafsa",
        "Question": "Daughter of Umer who married to Prophet was ?",
        "id": 179
    },
    {
        "Answer": "11",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "10",
        "Choice2": "11",
        "Choice3": "12",
        "Choice4": "13",
        "Question": "Qasim was born in ___________ years before Prophethood.",
        "id": 180
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Asad",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Ali",
        "Choice2": "Abu Bakar",
        "Choice3": "Umar",
        "Choice4": "Asad",
        "Question": "Hazrat __________ died first among the Sahabah.",
        "id": 181
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Refuge",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Flower",
        "Choice2": "Peace",
        "Choice3": "Rocks",
        "Choice4": "Refuge",
        "Question": "Surah means city of ?",
        "id": 182
    },
    {
        "Answer": "3",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "1",
        "Choice2": "2",
        "Choice3": " 3",
        "Choice4": "4",
        "Question": "How many surahs of the Holy Quran start with the word Sab-baha (سَبَّحَ)?",
        "id": 183
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ali (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Abu Bakar (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Ayesha (RA)",
        "Question": "_________ was the first person to offer Namaz amongst the Ummah of the Prophet (SA W).",
        "id": 184
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ayesha (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Choice3": " Hazrat Maria Qibtiya (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Safia (RA)",
        "Question": "_____________ Umm-ul-Momineen received salutation from Allah.",
        "id": 185
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ayesha (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Safia (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Maria Qibtiya (RA)",
        "Choice4": " Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Question": "___________ was the only Ummul Momineen who was not buried in Jannatul Baqi.",
        "id": 186
    },
    {
        "Answer": "40",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "25",
        "Choice2": "30",
        "Choice3": "35",
        "Choice4": "40",
        "Question": "What was the age of Hazrat Khadija (RA) when married to Hazrat Muhammad (SAW)?",
        "id": 187
    },
    {
        "Answer": "15",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " 5",
        "Choice2": "9",
        "Choice3": " 13",
        "Choice4": "15",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija (RA) was _______ years older than Hazrat Muhammad (SAW).",
        "id": 188
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " Hazrat Salma (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Memona (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Safia (RA)",
        "Question": "____________ died on the tenth of Ramadan 10 Nabvi.",
        "id": 189
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ayesha (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Maria Qibtiya (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Safia (RA)",
        "Question": "_____________ was buried at Jannat-e-Moalla in Macca.",
        "id": 190
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Banu Asad",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": " Banu Hashim",
        "Choice2": "Banu Khazeema",
        "Choice3": " Banu Asad",
        "Choice4": "Banu Atiyah",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija (RA) belonged to the tribe of __________.",
        "id": 191
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Hazrat Ruqia (RA)",
        "Choice2": "Hazrat Khadija (RA)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Maria Qibtiya (RA)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Safia (RA)",
        "Question": "Prophet (SAW) not offered funeral prayer of _________ due to Allah‘s will.",
        "id": 192
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ibrahim (R.A)",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Ibrahim (R.A)",
        "Choice2": " Abdullah (R.A)",
        "Choice3": "Hazrat Fatima (R.A)",
        "Choice4": "Hazrat Ruqaiyah (R.A)",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija (R.A) bore all the children of Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) except?",
        "id": 193
    },
    {
        "Answer": "First",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "First",
        "Choice2": "Second",
        "Choice3": "Third",
        "Choice4": "Fourth",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija (RA) was the ________ person to convert to Islam.",
        "id": 194
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khuwaylid ibn Asad",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Awwam bint khuwaylid",
        "Choice2": "Zubair ibn al-awam",
        "Choice3": "Asad ibne abd-ul- Uzza",
        "Choice4": "Khuwaylid ibn Asad",
        "Question": "What was the name of Hazrat Khadija (RA) father?",
        "id": 195
    },
    {
        "Answer": "First",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "First",
        "Choice2": "Second",
        "Choice3": "Third",
        "Choice4": "Fourth",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija (RA) was the ________ wife of Hazrat Muhammad (SAW).",
        "id": 196
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Two",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Two",
        "Choice2": "Three",
        "Choice3": "One",
        "Choice4": "Four",
        "Question": "How many sons Hazrat Khadija (RA) had with Hazrat Muhammad (SAW)?",
        "id": 197
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Friend",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Father",
        "Choice2": "Mother",
        "Choice3": "Brother",
        "Choice4": "Friend",
        "Question": "Who did Hazrat Khadija (RA) sent to ask Hazrat Muhammad (SAW) about marrying her?",
        "id": 198
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Fatima bint za’idah",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Fatima bint za’idah",
        "Choice2": "Umm kulthum",
        "Choice3": "Ruqiya bint Nawfal",
        "Choice4": "Zainab bint Hashim",
        "Question": "What was the name of Hazrat Khadija (RA) mother?",
        "id": 199
    },
    {
        "Answer": " 25",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "20",
        "Choice2": "23",
        "Choice3": " 25",
        "Choice4": "28",
        "Question": "Hazrat Khadija (RA) remained married monogamously with Hazrat Muhammad (SAW) for __________ years.",
        "id": 200
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Amman",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Syria",
        "Choice2": "Lebanon",
        "Choice3": "Amman",
        "Choice4": "Jordan",
        "Question": "Where is the grave of Hazrat Ayuob (AS)?",
        "id": 201
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Palestine",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Syria",
        "Choice2": "Lebanon",
        "Choice3": "Saudi Arabia",
        "Choice4": "Palestine",
        "Question": "Where is the grave of Hazrat Yaqub (AS)?",
        "id": 202
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Iraq",
        "Categ": "Islam",
        "Choice1": "Syria",
        "Choice2": "Lebanon",
        "Choice3": "Saudi Arabia",
        "Choice4": "Iraq",
        "Question": "Where is the grave of Hazrat Loot (A.S)?",
        "id": 203
    },
    {
        "Answer": "7th",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "7th",
        "Choice2": "8th",
        "Choice3": "9th",
        "Choice4": "10th",
        "Question": "Quaid-e-Azam reached Pakistan on……..August, 1947",
        "id": 204
    },
    {
        "Answer": "79",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "78",
        "Choice2": "80",
        "Choice3": "79",
        "Choice4": "72",
        "Question": "The First Constituent Assembly of Pakistan consisted of……..members at the time of the creation of Pakistan:",
        "id": 205
    },
    {
        "Answer": "December 25, 1876 ",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "December 24, 1876 ",
        "Choice2": "December 25, 1876 ",
        "Choice3": "December 20, 1876 ",
        "Choice4": "December 22, 1876 ",
        "Question": "What is the date of birth of Quaid-e-Azam\"",
        "id": 206
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Karachi",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Lahore",
        "Choice2": "Karachi",
        "Choice3": "Delhi",
        "Choice4": "Mumbai",
        "Question": "Where was Quaid-e-Azam born?",
        "id": 207
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1892",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1890",
        "Choice2": "1895",
        "Choice3": "1892",
        "Choice4": "1898",
        "Question": "When did Quaid-e-Azam first marry?",
        "id": 208
    },
    {
        "Answer": "December 1892",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "December 1892",
        "Choice2": "December 1894",
        "Choice3": "December 1895",
        "Choice4": "December 1893",
        "Question": "When did Quaid-e-Azam leave for England for higher studies?",
        "id": 209
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1896",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1897",
        "Choice2": "1895",
        "Choice3": "1892",
        "Choice4": "1896",
        "Question": " When did he return from England after completing his education?",
        "id": 210
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1902",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1897",
        "Choice2": "1895",
        "Choice3": "1892",
        "Choice4": "1902",
        "Question": "When did he become a member of Orient Club Bombay?",
        "id": 211
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1903",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1897",
        "Choice2": "1895",
        "Choice3": "1892",
        "Choice4": "1903",
        "Question": "When did he join Municipal Corporation Bombay as a legal advisor?",
        "id": 212
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Moulan Mazharuddin Shaheed",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Moulana Muhammad Ali Johar",
        "Choice2": "Moulan Mazharuddin Shaheed",
        "Choice3": "Allama Iqbal",
        "Choice4": "Sir Syed Ahmed Khan",
        "Question": "Who give the title “Quaid-e-Azam” to Muhammad Ali Jinnah?",
        "id": 213
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Valika Textile Mills",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Karachi Steel Mill",
        "Choice2": "Karachi Nuclear Power Plant",
        "Choice3": "Valika Textile Mills",
        "Choice4": "None",
        "Question": "After independence, the first industrial unit inaugurated by Quaid-e-Azam was__________ ?",
        "id": 214
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Rs 1",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Rs 1",
        "Choice2": "Rs 3",
        "Choice3": "Rs 4",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Quaid-e-Azam Muhammad Ali Jinnah fixed his salary as the Governor General of Pakistan at:",
        "id": 215
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Bombay ",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Delhi",
        "Choice2": "Calcutta",
        "Choice3": "Bombay ",
        "Choice4": "Dhaka",
        "Question": "Quaid-e-Azam started practice in which city of subcontinent?",
        "id": 216
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ziarat",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Quetta",
        "Choice2": "Sibi",
        "Choice3": "Ziarat",
        "Choice4": "Makran",
        "Question": "The Quaid-e-Azam stayed during his last illness in 1948 in ________ ?",
        "id": 217
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Allama Shabbir Ahmed Usmani",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Mufti Taqi Usmani",
        "Choice2": "Allama Shabbir Ahmed Usmani",
        "Choice3": "Mufti Rafi Usmani",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Who led the funeral prayer of Quaid-e-Azam Muhammad Ali Jinnah ?",
        "id": 218
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Gujrati",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Sindhi",
        "Choice2": "Baluchi",
        "Choice3": "Punjabi",
        "Choice4": "Gujrati",
        "Question": "Mother tongue of Quaid-e-Azam was ____________?",
        "id": 219
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1893",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1893",
        "Choice2": "1894",
        "Choice3": "1895",
        "Choice4": "1896",
        "Question": "Quaid-e-Azam first wife died in ________?",
        "id": 220
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Emibai",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Sakshi bai",
        "Choice2": "Ratan bai",
        "Choice3": " Emibai",
        "Choice4": "None",
        "Question": "_______ was the first wife of Quaid-e-Azam?",
        "id": 221
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Dawn daily",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Dawn weekly",
        "Choice2": "Pioneer",
        "Choice3": "Al Aman",
        "Choice4": "Dawn daily",
        "Question": "First Newspaper to use the title “Quaid-e-Azam” was ______________?",
        "id": 222
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1896",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1796",
        "Choice2": "1996",
        "Choice3": "1896",
        "Choice4": "1895",
        "Question": "When did Quaid-e-Azam start his legal practice in Bombay (Mumbai) ?",
        "id": 223
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Mithibai jinnah",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Emibai jinnah",
        "Choice2": "Rattanbai jinnah",
        "Choice3": " Mithibai jinnah",
        "Choice4": "Dinna Wadia",
        "Question": "Quaid-e-Azam mother name was___________?",
        "id": 224
    },
    {
        "Answer": "cricket",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "football",
        "Choice2": "hockey",
        "Choice3": "cricket",
        "Choice4": "squash",
        "Question": "Quaid-e-Azam trophy is the tournament of ?",
        "id": 225
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Yahya Merchant",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Yahya Merchant",
        "Choice2": "Ahmed Saeed",
        "Choice3": " Abdur Rab Nishtar",
        "Choice4": "Ahmad Hasan Dani",
        "Question": "Which one of these architect designed the Quaid-e-Azam tomb?",
        "id": 226
    },
    {
        "Answer": "98",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "87",
        "Choice2": "88",
        "Choice3": "97",
        "Choice4": "98",
        "Question": "Quaid-i-Azam’s daughter Dina Wadia passes away at the age of__________________ in New York?",
        "id": 227
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1938",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1935",
        "Choice2": "1932",
        "Choice3": "1938",
        "Choice4": "1939",
        "Question": "When Muhammad Ali jinnah was given the title of Quaid-e-Azam?",
        "id": 228
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Christopher Lee",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "Micky arther",
        "Choice2": "Christopher Lee",
        "Choice3": "Shashi Kapoor",
        "Choice4": " Jamil Dehalvi",
        "Question": "Who played role of Quaid-e-Azam in film “Jinnah” which was released 7 November 1998?",
        "id": 229
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1913",
        "Categ": "quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice1": "1911",
        "Choice2": "1912",
        "Choice3": "1913",
        "Choice4": "1914",
        "Question": "When did Quaid e Azam join All India Muslim league ?",
        "id": 230
    },
    {
        "Answer": "2009",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "2008",
        "Choice2": "2009",
        "Choice3": "2007",
        "Choice4": "2006",
        "Question": "When was IPL started?",
        "id": 231
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Lacrosse/Ice hockey",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Lacrosse/Ice hockey",
        "Choice2": "Cricket",
        "Choice3": "Field hockey",
        "Choice4": "Volleyball",
        "Question": "Which is the national sport of Canada?",
        "id": 232
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hockey",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Cricket",
        "Choice2": "Hockey",
        "Choice3": "Footbal",
        "Choice4": "Basebal",
        "Question": "Which is the national sport of Pakistan?",
        "id": 233
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cricket",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Cricket",
        "Choice2": "Footbal",
        "Choice3": "Hockey",
        "Choice4": "Basebal",
        "Question": "Which is the national sport of Pakistan?",
        "id": 234
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Bhutan",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Afghanistan",
        "Choice2": "Bhutan",
        "Choice3": "Japan",
        "Choice4": "India",
        "Question": "Archery is the national sport of which country?",
        "id": 235
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jamaica",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "India",
        "Choice2": "Sri Lanka",
        "Choice3": "Jamaica",
        "Choice4": "United States",
        "Question": " ____________ has Cricket as its national sports.",
        "id": 236
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Wrestling",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Wrestling",
        "Choice2": "Rugby union",
        "Choice3": "Golf",
        "Choice4": "Basketball",
        "Question": " _____________ is the national sport of Turkey",
        "id": 237
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1930",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1930",
        "Choice2": "1934",
        "Choice3": "1938",
        "Choice4": "1950",
        "Question": "When was the Commonwealth game started?",
        "id": 238
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Thailand",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Thailand",
        "Choice2": "Philippines",
        "Choice3": "South Korea",
        "Choice4": "China",
        "Question": "Which was the host country in 1998 for Asian Games?",
        "id": 239
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Doha",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Doha",
        "Choice2": "Bangkok",
        "Choice3": "New Delhi",
        "Choice4": "Tokyo",
        "Question": "Which city has hosted Asian Games in 2006?",
        "id": 240
    },
    {
        "Answer": "India",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "India",
        "Choice2": "Canada",
        "Choice3": "Malaysia",
        "Choice4": "Australia",
        "Question": "In which country commonwealth games were held in 2010?",
        "id": 241
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Kingston",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Kuala Lumpur",
        "Choice2": "Melbourne",
        "Choice3": "Kingston",
        "Choice4": "Perth",
        "Question": "Which city hosted commonwealth games in 1966?",
        "id": 242
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Australia",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "India",
        "Choice2": "Sri Lanka",
        "Choice3": "Windies",
        "Choice4": "Australia",
        "Question": "____________ has won Cricket world cup for the maximum number of times.",
        "id": 243
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Brazil",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Italy",
        "Choice2": "Uruguay",
        "Choice3": "West Germany",
        "Choice4": "Brazil",
        "Question": "Football World Cup has been won by which country for the maximum number of times?",
        "id": 244
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Canada",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Canada",
        "Choice2": "New Zealand",
        "Choice3": "England",
        "Choice4": "Scotland",
        "Question": "Which country has hosted Commonwealth Games for the maximum number of times?",
        "id": 245
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1951",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1951",
        "Choice2": "1954",
        "Choice3": "1958",
        "Choice4": "1962",
        "Question": "In which year Asian Games were started?",
        "id": 246
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Canada",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Canada",
        "Choice2": "New Zealand",
        "Choice3": "England",
        "Choice4": "Scotland",
        "Question": "First Olympic Games was held in ________",
        "id": 247
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Golf",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Bridge",
        "Choice2": "Billiards",
        "Choice3": "Golf",
        "Choice4": "Baseball",
        "Question": "Caddie is related to __________",
        "id": 248
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Uruguay",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Brazil",
        "Choice2": "Uruguay",
        "Choice3": "West Germany",
        "Choice4": "Italy",
        "Question": "Which country had started Football World?",
        "id": 249
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1975",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1975",
        "Choice2": "1979",
        "Choice3": "1983",
        "Choice4": "1976",
        "Question": "In which year Cricket world cup was first hosted by West Indies?",
        "id": 250
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Russia",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Russia",
        "Choice2": "Peru",
        "Choice3": "Latvia",
        "Choice4": "Lithuania",
        "Question": "Bandy is national sport of which country?",
        "id": 251
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Thailand",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "China",
        "Choice2": "India",
        "Choice3": "Japan",
        "Choice4": "Thailand",
        "Question": "Asian Games have been hosted by _________for maximum number of times.",
        "id": 252
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1916",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1912",
        "Choice2": "1920",
        "Choice3": "1916",
        "Choice4": "1944",
        "Question": "In which year Olympic Games were cancelled because of World War I?",
        "id": 253
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Deuce",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Deuce",
        "Choice2": "Dribble",
        "Choice3": "Double",
        "Choice4": "Dummy",
        "Question": "Which term is commonly used in Badminton and Volleyball?",
        "id": 254
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Upper Cut",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": " Mallet",
        "Choice2": "Upper Cut",
        "Choice3": "Bunder Chuckker",
        "Choice4": "Deuce",
        "Question": " ___________ is used in Boxing.",
        "id": 255
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Billiards",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Baseball",
        "Choice2": "Billiards",
        "Choice3": "Polo",
        "Choice4": "Bridge",
        "Question": "If we are using the following words in a game. Which game are we playing? Break, Cannons, Cue, In off, Jigger, Scratch",
        "id": 256
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1998",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1990",
        "Choice2": "1995",
        "Choice3": "1962",
        "Choice4": "1998",
        "Question": "In which year Football World Cup was held in France?",
        "id": 257
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Spain",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Italy",
        "Choice2": "Spain",
        "Choice3": "Brazil",
        "Choice4": "France",
        "Question": "Who was the winner of Football World Cup in 2010?",
        "id": 258
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Greece (1896)",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": " France (1894)",
        "Choice2": "Greece (1890)",
        "Choice3": "Greece (1896)",
        "Choice4": "France (1924)",
        "Question": "Olympic Games were first started by which country and in which year?",
        "id": 259
    },
    {
        "Answer": "204",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "204",
        "Choice2": "197",
        "Choice3": "199",
        "Choice4": "121",
        "Question": "How many nations participated in 2012 Olympic Games?",
        "id": 260
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1992",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1990",
        "Choice2": "1995",
        "Choice3": "1962",
        "Choice4": "1992",
        "Question": "In __________ Olympic Games were held in Spain.",
        "id": 261
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Atlanta",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "St. Louis",
        "Choice2": "Atlanta",
        "Choice3": "Los Angeles",
        "Choice4": "None of the above",
        "Question": "Which city of United States hosted Olympic Games in 1996?",
        "id": 262
    },
    {
        "Answer": "United Kingdom",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "United Kingdom",
        "Choice2": "China",
        "Choice3": "Greece",
        "Choice4": "Australia",
        "Question": "In 2012 which country hosted Olympic Games?",
        "id": 263
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Pune",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Delhi",
        "Choice2": "Pune",
        "Choice3": "Karachi",
        "Choice4": "Tamil Nadu",
        "Question": "Where did the game of Badminton originate?",
        "id": 264
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Don Budge",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Bill Tilden",
        "Choice2": "Don Budge",
        "Choice3": "Henry Vines",
        "Choice4": "Jack Kramer",
        "Question": "Who was the first person to win the Grand Slam in tennis?",
        "id": 265
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Mohun Bagan",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "United Sikkim",
        "Choice2": "Pailan Arrows",
        "Choice3": "Mohun Bagan",
        "Choice4": "Prayag United",
        "Question": "Which is the oldest football club in India?",
        "id": 266
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Pierre de Coubertin",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Demetrius Vikelas",
        "Choice2": "Jacques Rogge",
        "Choice3": "Juan Antonio Samaranch",
        "Choice4": "Pierre de Coubertin",
        "Question": "Who revived the Olympic Games?",
        "id": 267
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Goongi",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Amar",
        "Choice2": "Goongi",
        "Choice3": "Sanjeevani",
        "Choice4": "Gamini",
        "Question": "Which one of the following does not belong to the national styles of Kabaddi?",
        "id": 268
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1971",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1962",
        "Choice2": "1967",
        "Choice3": "1971",
        "Choice4": "1973",
        "Question": "When was the Tie-break introduced?",
        "id": 269
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1976",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1976",
        "Choice2": "1967",
        "Choice3": "1971",
        "Choice4": "1973",
        "Question": "When did Bjorn Borg win his first singles title?",
        "id": 270
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1977",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1977",
        "Choice2": "1976",
        "Choice3": "1980",
        "Choice4": "1988",
        "Question": "When was Wimbledon Lawn Tennis Museum opened?",
        "id": 271
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Goran Ivansevic",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Goran Ivansevic",
        "Choice2": "Fabrice Santoro",
        "Choice3": "Marin Cilic",
        "Choice4": "Mark Philippoussis",
        "Question": "Who won the men's singles title at Wimbledon as a wildcard?",
        "id": 272
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1894",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1854",
        "Choice2": "1874",
        "Choice3": "1894",
        "Choice4": "1898",
        "Question": "When was International Olympic Committee founded?",
        "id": 273
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1904",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1896",
        "Choice2": "1900",
        "Choice3": "1904",
        "Choice4": "1916",
        "Question": " When were gold, silver, bronze medals at Olympics introduced?",
        "id": 274
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Nawal El Moutawakel",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "Hassiba Boulmerka",
        "Choice2": "Nawal El Moutawakel",
        "Choice3": "Nezha Bidouane",
        "Choice4": "P. T. Usha",
        "Question": "Who won the inaugural women's 400 m hurdles event?",
        "id": 275
    },
    {
        "Answer": "3",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "2",
        "Choice2": "3",
        "Choice3": "4",
        "Choice4": "5",
        "Question": "How many times did Geet Sethi win the IBSF World Billiards title?",
        "id": 276
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1946",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1936",
        "Choice2": "1656",
        "Choice3": "1946",
        "Choice4": "1666",
        "Question": "When was Amateur Athletics Federation of India established?",
        "id": 277
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "2",
        "Choice2": "3",
        "Choice3": "4",
        "Choice4": "5",
        "Question": "How many gold medals did Carl Lewis win at the 1984 Olympic games?",
        "id": 278
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "sports",
        "Choice1": "1",
        "Choice2": "2",
        "Choice3": "3",
        "Choice4": "4",
        "Question": "How many gold medals did P. T. Usha win in the 1986 Seoul Asian Games?",
        "id": 279
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Nigeria",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Kenya",
        "Choice2": "Nigeria",
        "Choice3": "Ethiopia",
        "Choice4": " None of these",
        "Question": "Jare Ijalana, a girl from _________ is dubbed as the “Most beautiful girl in the world”?",
        "id": 282
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "2",
        "Choice2": "3",
        "Choice3": "4",
        "Choice4": "5",
        "Question": "The Kurdistan region spans over _____ countries?",
        "id": 283
    },
    {
        "Answer": "English and French",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "English and French",
        "Choice2": " English and German",
        "Choice3": "English and Spanish",
        "Choice4": " English, French and German",
        "Question": "The two official languages of NATO are_______________?",
        "id": 284
    },
    {
        "Answer": "New York",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Washington",
        "Choice2": "New York",
        "Choice3": "Berlin",
        "Choice4": "Brussels",
        "Question": "The headquarter of Human Rights Watch (HRW) is located in_____________?",
        "id": 285
    },
    {
        "Answer": "London",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": " New York",
        "Choice2": "Berlin",
        "Choice3": "Moscow",
        "Choice4": "London",
        "Question": "The World’s first underground railway system was built in___________?",
        "id": 286
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The Republican Party",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "The Republican Party",
        "Choice2": "Liberal Part",
        "Choice3": "Labour Party",
        "Choice4": "Democratic Party",
        "Question": "Grand Old Party is also known as _________?",
        "id": 287
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Italy",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Germany",
        "Choice2": "Russia",
        "Choice3": "Italy",
        "Choice4": "America",
        "Question": "What country did Benito Mussolini rule?",
        "id": 288
    },
    {
        "Answer": "15",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "5",
        "Choice2": "10",
        "Choice3": "15",
        "Choice4": "20",
        "Question": "How many Judges are in the International Court of Justice (ICJ)?",
        "id": 289
    },
    {
        "Answer": "China",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Russia",
        "Choice2": "USA",
        "Choice3": "China",
        "Choice4": "India",
        "Question": "Which Country in the World has most Neighbors ?",
        "id": 290
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Skaats Wheeler",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Arthur Schimit",
        "Choice2": "Alfered Nobel",
        "Choice3": "Skaats Wheeler",
        "Choice4": " None of these",
        "Question": "Fan was invented by___________?",
        "id": 291
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ameer Kror",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Khushal Khan Khatak",
        "Choice2": "Ameer Kror",
        "Choice3": " Rahman Baba",
        "Choice4": " None of these",
        "Question": "Who is considered the first poet of Pashto Language?",
        "id": 292
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khalid Bin Saeed",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": " K. K. Aziz",
        "Choice2": "Khalid Bin Saeed",
        "Choice3": "Aitzaz Ahsan",
        "Choice4": "Syed Ameer Ali",
        "Question": "The book ” Pakistan: the Formative Phase” was written by__________?",
        "id": 293
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sher Shah Suri",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Altimush",
        "Choice2": "Muhammad Taghluq",
        "Choice3": "Feroz Taghluq",
        "Choice4": "Sher Shah Suri",
        "Question": "G.T Road was constructed by __________?",
        "id": 294
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jamshoro",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Dadu",
        "Choice2": "Jamshoro",
        "Choice3": "Hala",
        "Choice4": "Sukkur",
        "Question": "Which city of Sindh is famous for ‘Pallo’ (Fish)?",
        "id": 295
    },
    {
        "Answer": "General Ayoub Khan",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Sir Syed Ahmed Khan",
        "Choice2": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "Choice3": "Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto",
        "Choice4": "General Ayoub Khan",
        "Question": "The book ” Friends not Masters” was written by____________?",
        "id": 296
    },
    {
        "Answer": "England",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "France",
        "Choice2": "USA",
        "Choice3": "England",
        "Choice4": "Canada",
        "Question": "Shakespeare beach is located in which country?",
        "id": 297
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Barometer",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Clock",
        "Choice2": "Airship",
        "Choice3": "Barometer",
        "Choice4": "Cotton gin",
        "Question": "Which of the following was invented by Torricelli?",
        "id": 298
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Physicist",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": " Physicist",
        "Choice2": "Physician",
        "Choice3": "Chemist",
        "Choice4": "Biologist",
        "Question": "Albert Einstein was a____________?",
        "id": 299
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Owl",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Hen",
        "Choice2": "Peacock",
        "Choice3": "Eagle",
        "Choice4": "Owl",
        "Question": "Bubo bubo is the scientific name of which of the following species?",
        "id": 300
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ameer Kror",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Khushal Khan Khatak",
        "Choice2": "Ameer Kror",
        "Choice3": "Rahman Baba",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Who is considered the first poet of Pashto Language?",
        "id": 301
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Excitement",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Excitement",
        "Choice2": "Class",
        "Choice3": "Realization",
        "Choice4": "Swiftness",
        "Question": "Synonym of fervor is__________?",
        "id": 302
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sad",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Sad",
        "Choice2": "Happy",
        "Choice3": "Famous",
        "Choice4": "Enemy",
        "Question": "Synonym of Doleful is__________?",
        "id": 303
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Appropriate",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Whole",
        "Choice2": "Revealing",
        "Choice3": "Cooked",
        "Choice4": "Appropriate",
        "Question": "Synonym of Apposite is__________?",
        "id": 304
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Shy",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Upsetting",
        "Choice2": "Shy",
        "Choice3": "Responsible",
        "Choice4": "Polite",
        "Question": "Synonym of Diffident is__________?",
        "id": 305
    },
    {
        "Answer": "KPK",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Sindh",
        "Choice2": "Punjab",
        "Choice3": "Balochistan",
        "Choice4": "KPK",
        "Question": "In which province Tanda Dam is located?",
        "id": 306
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Dashat River",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Gomal River",
        "Choice2": "Dashat River",
        "Choice3": "Kabul River",
        "Choice4": "Indus River",
        "Question": "On which river the Mirani dam was constructed?",
        "id": 307
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khalid Bin Saeed",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "K. K. Aziz",
        "Choice2": "Khalid Bin Saeed",
        "Choice3": "Aitzaz Ahsan",
        "Choice4": "Syed Ameer Ali",
        "Question": "The book ” Pakistan: the Formative Phase” was written by__________?",
        "id": 308
    },
    {
        "Answer": "William Harvey",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Carl Linnaeus",
        "Choice2": " Francis Crik",
        "Choice3": "Robert. Brown",
        "Choice4": "William Harvey",
        "Question": "Who discovered blood circulation?",
        "id": 309
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sher Shah Suri",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Altimush",
        "Choice2": "Muhammad Taghluq",
        "Choice3": " Feroz Taghluq",
        "Choice4": "Sher Shah Suri",
        "Question": "G.T Road was constructed by __________?",
        "id": 310
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Robert Fluton",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": " James Watt",
        "Choice2": "Robert Fluton",
        "Choice3": "Frank Whittle",
        "Choice4": "George Stephenson",
        "Question": "Who invented steamboat?",
        "id": 311
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Leukocytes",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Erythrocytes",
        "Choice2": "Leukocytes",
        "Choice3": "Thrombocytes",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Other name of white blood cells is _____________?",
        "id": 312
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Thrombocytes",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Erythrocytes",
        "Choice2": "Leukocytes",
        "Choice3": "Thrombocytes",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Other name of platelets _______?",
        "id": 313
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Erythrocytes",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Erythrocytes",
        "Choice2": "Leukocytes",
        "Choice3": "Thrombocytes",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Other name of red blood cells is ____________?",
        "id": 314
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jamshoro",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Dadu",
        "Choice2": "Jamshoro",
        "Choice3": "Hala",
        "Choice4": "Sukkur",
        "Question": "Which city of Sindh is famous for ‘Pallo’ (Fish)?",
        "id": 315
    },
    {
        "Answer": "General Ayoub Khan",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Sir Syed Ahmed Khan",
        "Choice2": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "Choice3": "Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto",
        "Choice4": "General Ayoub Khan",
        "Question": "The book ” Friends not Masters” was written by____________?",
        "id": 316
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Discount",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Gift",
        "Choice2": "Charity",
        "Choice3": "Commission",
        "Choice4": "Discount",
        "Question": "Synonym of rebate is ____________ ?",
        "id": 317
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Destroy",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Destroy",
        "Choice2": "Promote",
        "Choice3": "Disfigure",
        "Choice4": "Dissipate",
        "Question": "Synonym of Decimate is _________?",
        "id": 318
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Think",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Help",
        "Choice2": "Discourage",
        "Choice3": "Think",
        "Choice4": "Provoke",
        "Question": "Synonym of Mull is __________ ?",
        "id": 319
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Faridpur 1781",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Faridpur 1767",
        "Choice2": "Faridpur 1781",
        "Choice3": "Sylhet 1767",
        "Choice4": "Sylhet 1768",
        "Question": "When and where did Haji Shariatullah born?",
        "id": 320
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1976",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "1974",
        "Choice2": "1975",
        "Choice3": "1976",
        "Choice4": "1977",
        "Question": "When did PTV start its colour transmission?",
        "id": 321
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Abu Sufyan",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Shaiba",
        "Choice2": "Abu Jahal",
        "Choice3": "Abu Sufyan",
        "Choice4": "Khalid bin Walid",
        "Question": "Who was the commanders of the Infidels in the Battle of Uhud?",
        "id": 322
    },
    {
        "Answer": "England",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "France",
        "Choice2": "USA",
        "Choice3": "England",
        "Choice4": "Canada",
        "Question": "Shakespeare beach is located in which country?",
        "id": 323
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Barometer",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Clock",
        "Choice2": "Airship",
        "Choice3": "Barometer",
        "Choice4": "Cotton gin",
        "Question": "Which of the following was invented by Torricelli?",
        "id": 324
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Physicist",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Physicist",
        "Choice2": "Physician",
        "Choice3": "Chemist",
        "Choice4": "Biologist",
        "Question": "Albert Einstein was a____________?",
        "id": 325
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Owl",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Hen",
        "Choice2": "Peacock",
        "Choice3": "Eagle",
        "Choice4": "Owl",
        "Question": "Bubo bubo is the scientific name of which of the following species?",
        "id": 326
    },
    {
        "Answer": "World Cancer Day",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": " World Day of the Sick",
        "Choice2": "World Alzheimer’s Day",
        "Choice3": "World Day of Social Justice",
        "Choice4": "World Cancer Day",
        "Question": "Which day is celebrated on 4th February?",
        "id": 327
    },
    {
        "Answer": "N-35",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "N-655",
        "Choice2": "N-35",
        "Choice3": "N-25",
        "Choice4": "N-135",
        "Question": "Karakoram highway is also known as___________?",
        "id": 328
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Oman",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Iran",
        "Choice2": "Oman",
        "Choice3": "UAE",
        "Choice4": " Saudi Arabia",
        "Question": "The only country with which Pakistan shares a maritime border (not the land border) is__________?",
        "id": 329
    },
    {
        "Answer": "All of these",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "James peebles",
        "Choice2": " Michel Mayor",
        "Choice3": "Didier Queloz",
        "Choice4": "All of these",
        "Question": "Which of the following has won the 2019 noble prize winner in physics?",
        "id": 330
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hafulizullah Amin",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Hamid Karzai",
        "Choice2": "Barbark Kermal",
        "Choice3": "Hafulizullah Amin",
        "Choice4": "Haji Mohd Chamkani",
        "Question": "Who was Afghan ruler at the time of USSR invasion?",
        "id": 331
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Deng Xiaoping",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Deng Xiaoping",
        "Choice2": "Li Kuwan Yu",
        "Choice3": "Wang Yi",
        "Choice4": "Xi Jing Ping",
        "Question": "Who is considered as the Leader of Modern Chinese Economy?",
        "id": 332
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Chile",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "China",
        "Choice2": "India",
        "Choice3": "Chile",
        "Choice4": "Russia",
        "Question": "World’s largest Copper producer is__________?",
        "id": 333
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Banu Taym",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Banu Sahm",
        "Choice2": " Banu Taym",
        "Choice3": "Banu Hashim",
        "Choice4": " Banu Asad",
        "Question": "Hazrat Abu Bakr (R.A) belonged to the tribe of__________?",
        "id": 334
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Lilly",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Rose",
        "Choice2": "Lilly",
        "Choice3": "Rafflesia",
        "Choice4": "Tulip",
        "Question": "Which of the following flower is called Queen of Water?",
        "id": 335
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Rafflesia",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Conifer",
        "Choice2": "Fern",
        "Choice3": "Rafflesia",
        "Choice4": "Horsetail",
        "Question": "What is the largest flower in the world?",
        "id": 336
    },
    {
        "Answer": "180",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "90",
        "Choice2": "180",
        "Choice3": "270",
        "Choice4": "360",
        "Question": "How many latitude lines are there?",
        "id": 337
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Aristotle",
        "Choice2": "Fransco Redi",
        "Choice3": "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Choice4": "Rachel Carson",
        "Question": "Who is the known as the father of taxonomy?",
        "id": 338
    },
    {
        "Answer": "ATP",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "ADP",
        "Choice2": "DNA",
        "Choice3": "RNA",
        "Choice4": "ATP",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a currency of Body cells?",
        "id": 339
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Tannic",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Valeric",
        "Choice2": "Acetic",
        "Choice3": "Formic",
        "Choice4": "Tannic",
        "Question": "Which of the following acid is used in Ink?",
        "id": 340
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Herber process",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": " Herber process",
        "Choice2": "Regrigration process",
        "Choice3": "Contact process",
        "Choice4": "All of these",
        "Question": "How is ammonia synthesized?",
        "id": 341
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Mathematics",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Biology",
        "Choice2": "Mathematics",
        "Choice3": "Physics",
        "Choice4": "Chemistry",
        "Question": "Which of the following science is considered “mother of all sciences”?",
        "id": 342
    },
    {
        "Answer": "J",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "X",
        "Choice2": "K",
        "Choice3": "J",
        "Choice4": "N",
        "Question": "Which of the following letter does not represent in periodic table?",
        "id": 343
    },
    {
        "Answer": "South Pole",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "South Pole",
        "Choice2": "North Pole",
        "Choice3": "Both A and B",
        "Choice4": "None of These",
        "Question": "There is a hole in the Ozone Layer at__________?",
        "id": 344
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Pakistan and Saudi Arabia",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Pakistan and Afghanistan",
        "Choice2": "Pakistan and Saudi Arabia",
        "Choice3": "akistan and Iran",
        "Choice4": "Pakistan and China",
        "Question": "The “Treaty of Friendship” was signed in 1951 between?",
        "id": 345
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1980",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "1978",
        "Choice2": "1979",
        "Choice3": "1980",
        "Choice4": "1981",
        "Question": "When the Federal Shariat Court established?",
        "id": 346
    },
    {
        "Answer": "KNESSET",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "National Assembly",
        "Choice2": "General Council",
        "Choice3": "KNESSET",
        "Choice4": "Federal Parliament",
        "Question": "What is the name of Israel’s Parliament?",
        "id": 347
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1878",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "1875",
        "Choice2": "1876",
        "Choice3": "1877",
        "Choice4": "1878",
        "Question": "When did Muhammad Ali Johar born?",
        "id": 348
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Aitzaz Ahsan",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Aitzaz Ahsan",
        "Choice2": "K.K Aziz",
        "Choice3": "Chudary Muhammad Ali",
        "Choice4": "Chudary Khaliquzzaman",
        "Question": "Who wrote “The Indus Saga and Making of Pakistan”?",
        "id": 349
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto",
        "Categ": "general_knowledge",
        "Choice1": "Benzir Bhutto",
        "Choice2": "Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto",
        "Choice3": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Choice4": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Question": "Who wrote book “If I am assassinated”?",
        "id": 350
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Thomas Alva Edison",
        "Choice2": "Galileo",
        "Choice3": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Choice4": "G. Marconi",
        "Question": "Who invented the telephone?",
        "id": 351
    },
    {
        "Answer": "George Stephenson",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Charles Babbage",
        "Choice2": "Isaac Newton",
        "Choice3": "James Watt",
        "Choice4": "George Stephenson",
        "Question": "Who invented the railway engine?",
        "id": 352
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Robert Watson Watt",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Henrey Backquerel",
        "Choice2": "Max Planck",
        "Choice3": "Robert Watson Watt",
        "Choice4": "Humphrey Davy",
        "Question": "Who invented Radar?",
        "id": 353
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Albert Sabin",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Albert Sabin",
        "Choice2": "Burkholder",
        "Choice3": "Luise Pasture",
        "Choice4": "Jonas Salk",
        "Question": "Who invented polio vaccine (oral)?",
        "id": 354
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Eduard Jenner",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Eduard Jenner",
        "Choice2": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Choice3": "Albert Einstein",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "Who developed the small pox vaccination?",
        "id": 355
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Helium",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Helium",
        "Choice2": "Neon",
        "Choice3": "Xenon",
        "Choice4": "Krypton",
        "Question": "Which one of the following was to be discovered first in the chromosphere of the sun",
        "id": 356
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Edwin Land",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": " Thomas Alva Edison",
        "Choice2": "James Watt",
        "Choice3": "Albert Einstein",
        "Choice4": "Edwin Land",
        "Question": "Which famous inventor ranks second in the number of patents registered?",
        "id": 357
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jacques Cousteau",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Thomas Edison",
        "Choice2": "Isaac Newton",
        "Choice3": " Leonardo da Vinci",
        "Choice4": "Jacques Cousteau",
        "Question": "What famous scientist and inventor participated in the invention of the Aqua-Lung?",
        "id": 358
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Charles Goodyear",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Charles Goodyear",
        "Choice2": "William Stockes",
        "Choice3": "J.E.Lundstrom",
        "Choice4": "Sir Joseph Swann",
        "Question": "Vulcanised rubber was invented by",
        "id": 359
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Louis Braille",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": " Louis Braille",
        "Choice2": "Henry Bacquerel",
        "Choice3": "Sir J.A.Fleming",
        "Choice4": "Dr.Charles H. Townes",
        "Question": "The system for writing by blind people was invented by",
        "id": 360
    },
    {
        "Answer": "James Watt",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "William Stockes",
        "Choice2": "J.E.Lundstrom",
        "Choice3": "Sir Joseph Swann",
        "Choice4": "James Watt",
        "Question": "The steam engine was invented by",
        "id": 361
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Samuel Colt",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Eduard Jenner",
        "Choice2": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Choice3": "Albert Einstein",
        "Choice4": "Samuel Colt",
        "Question": "The revolver was invented by",
        "id": 362
    },
    {
        "Answer": "J.Perkins",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "J.Perkins",
        "Choice2": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Choice3": "Albert Einstein",
        "Choice4": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Question": "The refrigerator was invented by",
        "id": 363
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Enrico Ferni",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Enrico Ferni",
        "Choice2": "Eduard Jenner",
        "Choice3": " Alexander Fleming",
        "Choice4": "Albert Einstein Torricelli",
        "Question": "The nuclear reactor was invented by",
        "id": 364
    },
    {
        "Answer": " Archimedes",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Pierre Simon de Laplace",
        "Choice2": " Archimedes",
        "Choice3": "Edwin Hubble",
        "Choice4": "Joseph J. Thomson",
        "Question": "The laws of floating bodies was discovered by",
        "id": 365
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Karl Landsteiner",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Richard Feynman",
        "Choice2": "Karl Landsteiner",
        "Choice3": "Alfred Wegener",
        "Choice4": "Stephen Hawking",
        "Question": "The four blood groups were discovered by",
        "id": 366
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Frederick Soddy",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Emil Kraepelin",
        "Choice2": "Trofim Lysenko",
        "Choice3": "Frederick Soddy",
        "Choice4": "Francis Galton",
        "Question": "The existence of isotopes was discovered by",
        "id": 367
    },
    {
        "Answer": "William Einthoven",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "B. F. Goodrich",
        "Choice2": "Gottlieb Daimler",
        "Choice3": "Karl Benz",
        "Choice4": "William Einthoven",
        "Question": "The electro-cardiograph was invented by",
        "id": 368
    },
    {
        "Answer": "William Stockes",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "William Shockley",
        "Choice2": "Tim Berners Lee",
        "Choice3": "Chester Carlson",
        "Choice4": "William Stockes",
        "Question": "Stethoscope was invented by",
        "id": 369
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sir Richard Arkwright",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Charles Macintosh",
        "Choice2": " Antoine Joseph Sax",
        "Choice3": "Samuel Morse",
        "Choice4": "Sir Richard Arkwright",
        "Question": "Spinning frame was invented by",
        "id": 370
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sir Humphry Davy",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Sir Humphry Davy",
        "Choice2": "James Watson",
        "Choice3": "John Bardeen",
        "Choice4": "John von Neumann",
        "Question": "Sodium was discovered by",
        "id": 371
    },
    {
        "Answer": "J.E.Lundstrom",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Levi Strauss",
        "Choice2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Choice3": "Peter Goldmark",
        "Choice4": "J.E.Lundstrom",
        "Question": "Safety matches was invented by",
        "id": 372
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sir Joseph Swann",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Sir Joseph Swann",
        "Choice2": "Adolph Rickenbacker",
        "Choice3": "David Brewster",
        "Choice4": "Christopher Cockerell",
        "Question": "Rayon was invented by",
        "id": 373
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Marie and Pierrie Curie",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Willard Libby",
        "Choice2": "Edward Teller",
        "Choice3": " Ernst Haeckel",
        "Choice4": "Marie and Pierrie Curie",
        "Question": "Radium was discovered by",
        "id": 374
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Henry Bacquerel",
        "Categ": "inventions",
        "Choice1": "Karl Landsteiner",
        "Choice2": "Konrad Lorenz",
        "Choice3": "Henry Bacquerel",
        "Choice4": "Edward O. Wilson",
        "Question": "Radioactivity was discovered by",
        "id": 375
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Quaid-e-Azam",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "Choice2": "Quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice3": "Moulvi Tameez-ud-Din",
        "Choice4": "Sardar Abdur Rab Nishtar",
        "Question": "Who was the first President of the Constituent Assembly of Pakistan?",
        "id": 376
    },
    {
        "Answer": "9 years",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "5 years",
        "Choice2": "7 years",
        "Choice3": "9 years",
        "Choice4": "11 years",
        "Question": "After how many years Pakistan got its first constitution?",
        "id": 377
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Objective Resolution",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Representative Act",
        "Choice2": "Pakistan Act",
        "Choice3": "Independence Act",
        "Choice4": "Objective Resolution",
        "Question": "What document was firstly drafted to give pace to constitution making process?",
        "id": 378
    },
    {
        "Answer": "12th March 1949",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "14th February 1949",
        "Choice2": "12th March 1949",
        "Choice3": "9th June 1949",
        "Choice4": "15th August 1949",
        "Question": "When the Constituent Assembly passed the Objective Resolution?",
        "id": 379
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Bombay",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Delhi",
        "Choice2": "Bombay",
        "Choice3": "Kanpur",
        "Choice4": "Allahabad",
        "Question": "In which of the following cities Indian National Congress was found?",
        "id": 380
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Dhaka",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Delhi",
        "Choice2": "Lahore",
        "Choice3": "Dhaka",
        "Choice4": "Allahabad",
        "Question": "In which of the following cities All India Muslim League was found?",
        "id": 381
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Lord Curzon",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Lord Curzon",
        "Choice2": "Lord Wavell",
        "Choice3": " Lord Minto",
        "Choice4": "Lord Algan",
        "Question": "Who was the Viceroy of India at the time of partition of Bengal?",
        "id": 382
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sir Agha Khan",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Sir Agha Khan",
        "Choice2": " Nawab Waqar ul Mulk",
        "Choice3": "Nawab Saleem ullah Khan",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "Who was the first President of All India Muslim League?",
        "id": 383
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1889",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "1886",
        "Choice2": "1887",
        "Choice3": "1888",
        "Choice4": "1889",
        "Question": "In which year Ali Garh Trusteeship bill was passed?",
        "id": 384
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1897",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "1895",
        "Choice2": "1896",
        "Choice3": "1897",
        "Choice4": "1898",
        "Question": "In which year Syed Jamal-u-din Afghani died?",
        "id": 385
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Nisar Ali",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Nisar Ali",
        "Choice2": " Sayed Ahmad",
        "Choice3": "Muhammad Ali",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "What was the real name of Titu Mir?",
        "id": 386
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khyber Pass",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Khunjerab Pass",
        "Choice2": "Khyber Pass",
        "Choice3": "Tochi Pass",
        "Choice4": "Gomal Pass",
        "Question": "Which pass connects Pakistan with Afghanistan?",
        "id": 387
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Skaser",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Nanga Parbat",
        "Choice2": "Skaser",
        "Choice3": "Malka Parbat",
        "Choice4": "Everest",
        "Question": "The highest peak of Salt Range is?",
        "id": 388
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Kirthar Range",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Himalaya",
        "Choice2": "Karakoram Range",
        "Choice3": "Kirthar Range",
        "Choice4": "Salt Range",
        "Question": "Which mountain range is located in Sindh Province?",
        "id": 389
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Chaghi Hills",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Kohe-e-Sufaid",
        "Choice2": "Chaghi Hills",
        "Choice3": "Toba Kakar",
        "Choice4": "Raskoh",
        "Question": "Pakistan conducted nuclear tests on May 28, 1998 at?",
        "id": 390
    },
    {
        "Answer": "205,344 Sq Km",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "74,521 Km",
        "Choice2": "40,914 Km",
        "Choice3": "347,190 Sq Km",
        "Choice4": "205,344 Sq Km",
        "Question": "What is the total area of Punjab Province?",
        "id": 391
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Gilgit",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Ghanchay",
        "Choice2": "Nagar",
        "Choice3": "Chilas",
        "Choice4": "Gilgit",
        "Question": "The capital city of Gilgit Baltistan is?",
        "id": 392
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Quaid-e-Azam",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "Choice2": "Z.A Sulehri",
        "Choice3": "Quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice4": " None of them",
        "Question": "Who was the founder of Daily English Newspaper Dawn?",
        "id": 393
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Karachi",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Lahore",
        "Choice2": "Gwadar",
        "Choice3": "Karachi",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "Pakistan Steel Mills is located in?",
        "id": 394
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Kh. Nazim-ud-Din",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Ch Muhammad Ali",
        "Choice2": "Kh. Nazim-ud-Din",
        "Choice3": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "Choice4": "Feroze Khan Noon",
        "Question": "Who was the second Prime Minister of Pakistan?",
        "id": 395
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Islamabad Capital Territory",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Islamabad capital total",
        "Choice2": " Islamabad city tribes",
        "Choice3": "Islamabad Capital Territory",
        "Choice4": "Islamabad city territory",
        "Question": "ICT stands for?",
        "id": 396
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khutba-Hajjat-ul-Vida",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "International Charter",
        "Choice2": "U.N. Charter",
        "Choice3": "Khutba-Hajjat-ul-Vida",
        "Choice4": "French Constitution",
        "Question": "First Charter of Human Rights is?",
        "id": 397
    },
    {
        "Answer": "371",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "275",
        "Choice2": "371",
        "Choice3": "237",
        "Choice4": "100",
        "Question": "The members of Punjab Assembly are?",
        "id": 398
    },
    {
        "Answer": "5 years",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "4 years",
        "Choice2": "5 years",
        "Choice3": "6 years",
        "Choice4": "3 years",
        "Question": "Tenure of National and Provincial Assemblies is?",
        "id": 399
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Two",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "One",
        "Choice2": "Two",
        "Choice3": "Three",
        "Choice4": "Four",
        "Question": "Number of houses of Pakistan’s Majlis-e-Shura (Parliament) is?",
        "id": 400
    },
    {
        "Answer": "President",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Army Chief",
        "Choice2": "Prime Minister",
        "Choice3": "President",
        "Choice4": "Governor",
        "Question": "The Supreme commander of Pakistan Armed Forces is?",
        "id": 401
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sui Northern Gas Pipelines limited",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Sui Northern Gas Pipelines Lahore",
        "Choice2": "Sui Northern Gas Pipelines limited",
        "Choice3": "Sui Northern Gas Pakistan limited",
        "Choice4": " Sui Northern Gas Punjab limited",
        "Question": "SNGPL stands for?",
        "id": 402
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Faisalabad",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Faisalabad",
        "Choice2": "Rawalpindi",
        "Choice3": "Sialkot",
        "Choice4": "Hyderabad",
        "Question": "The third largest city of Pakistan is",
        "id": 403
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1951",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "1950",
        "Choice2": "1951",
        "Choice3": "1952",
        "Choice4": "1953",
        "Question": "First Census was held in Pakistan in the year?",
        "id": 404
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Muhammad Bin Qasim",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Mahmood Ghaznavi",
        "Choice2": "Zaheer-ud-Din Baber",
        "Choice3": "Muhammad Bin Qasim",
        "Choice4": "Aurangzeb Alamgir",
        "Question": "The Muslims came to Sindh in 712 A.D.under the leadership of?",
        "id": 405
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Chaj",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Gandhara",
        "Choice2": "Chaj",
        "Choice3": "Taxila",
        "Choice4": "Harrapa",
        "Question": "The area between rivers Jhelum and Chenab is called?",
        "id": 406
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Lahore",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Gujranwala",
        "Choice2": "Multan",
        "Choice3": "Karachi",
        "Choice4": "Lahore",
        "Question": "The largest Railway workshop Mughalpura is situated in?",
        "id": 407
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sahiwal",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Multan",
        "Choice2": "Okara",
        "Choice3": "Lahore",
        "Choice4": "Sahiwal",
        "Question": "The ruins of Harrapa are situated in district?",
        "id": 408
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Painting",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Construction",
        "Choice2": "Music",
        "Choice3": "Painting",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "Abdul Rehman Chughtai was attached with the art of?",
        "id": 409
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Pakistan",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "India",
        "Choice2": "Iran",
        "Choice3": "Pakistan",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "Which is the sixth most populated country of the world?",
        "id": 410
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Punjab",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Sindh",
        "Choice2": "Gilgit",
        "Choice3": "KPK",
        "Choice4": "Punjab",
        "Question": "Thal desert is located in?",
        "id": 411
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Dhaka",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Madras",
        "Choice2": "Karachi",
        "Choice3": "Dhaka",
        "Choice4": "Delhi",
        "Question": "The founder of All India Muslim League Nawab Salimullah Khan belonged to?",
        "id": 412
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Baba Farid",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Baba Farid",
        "Choice2": "Shah Hussain",
        "Choice3": "Bullhay Shah",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "Who is the first Punjab poet?",
        "id": 413
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Major Raja Aziz Bhatti",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Major Raja Aziz Bhatti",
        "Choice2": "Major Tufail",
        "Choice3": "Lalik Jan",
        "Choice4": "Mulla Faqir",
        "Question": "Who was the hero of Pak India 1965 war?",
        "id": 414
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Shah Abdul Latif Bhatai",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Khushal Khan Khattak",
        "Choice2": "Waris Shah",
        "Choice3": "Makhdum Muhammad Hashim",
        "Choice4": "Shah Abdul Latif Bhatai",
        "Question": "The name of poet whose collection of poetry is called “Shah jo Risalu”?",
        "id": 415
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Pata Khazana",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Pata Khazana",
        "Choice2": "Tazkra-tul-Aulia",
        "Choice3": "Jat di Kartut",
        "Choice4": "Aasar-ul-Sanadeed",
        "Question": "Which is the first book of Pushto language?",
        "id": 416
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Army",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Wth",
        "Choice2": "Arms",
        "Choice3": "Army",
        "Choice4": "Literature",
        "Question": "Urdu is a word of Turkish language, it means?",
        "id": 417
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Shaikh Muhammad Ikram",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Amir Khusro",
        "Choice2": "Shaikh Muhammad Ikram",
        "Choice3": "Mir Taqi Mir",
        "Choice4": "Khawaja Mir Dard",
        "Question": "Who wrote “Mauj-e-Kausar”?",
        "id": 418
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sindhi",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Punjabi",
        "Choice2": "Kashmiri",
        "Choice3": "Sindhi",
        "Choice4": "Balochi",
        "Question": "Name the language in which the Holy Quran was translated for the first time in India?",
        "id": 419
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1967",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "1940",
        "Choice2": "1950",
        "Choice3": "1967",
        "Choice4": "1970",
        "Question": "Madr-e-Millat Fatima Jinnah died in the year?",
        "id": 420
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Urdu",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "English",
        "Choice2": "Hindi",
        "Choice3": "Urdu",
        "Choice4": "Punjabi",
        "Question": "Ahmad Shah Pitras Bukhari was a famous writer of ______ language.",
        "id": 421
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Quaid-e-Azam",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Quaid-e-Azam",
        "Choice2": "Malik Ghulam Muhammad",
        "Choice3": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "Choice4": "Allama Muhammad Iqbal",
        "Question": "Who inaugurated the State Bank of Pakistan?",
        "id": 422
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Punjab",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Gilgit Baltistan",
        "Choice2": "KPK",
        "Choice3": "Punjab",
        "Choice4": "Sindh",
        "Question": "Sardar Abdur Rub Nishtar was the Governor of?",
        "id": 423
    },
    {
        "Answer": "PK",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "PAK",
        "Choice2": "PK",
        "Choice3": " PAK 1",
        "Choice4": "None of them",
        "Question": "National code of Pakistan is?",
        "id": 424
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
        "Categ": "pakistan",
        "Choice1": "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
        "Choice2": "Punjab",
        "Choice3": "Sindh",
        "Choice4": "Balochistan",
        "Question": "Where is Warsak Dam of Pakistan situated?",
        "id": 425
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Neptune",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Mercury",
        "Choice2": "Pluto",
        "Choice3": "Neptune",
        "Choice4": "Uranus",
        "Question": "Which is the outermost planet in the solar system?",
        "id": 426
    },
    {
        "Answer": "rickets",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "scurvy",
        "Choice2": "rickets",
        "Choice3": "night blindness",
        "Choice4": "osteomalacia",
        "Question": "Severe deficiency of Vitamin D results in __________.",
        "id": 427
    },
    {
        "Answer": "80%",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "70%",
        "Choice2": "75%",
        "Choice3": "80%",
        "Choice4": "90%",
        "Question": "Milk contains water",
        "id": 428
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Coulomb",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Ampere",
        "Choice2": "Coulomb",
        "Choice3": "Ohm",
        "Choice4": "Volt",
        "Question": "The SI unit of charge is __________?",
        "id": 429
    },
    {
        "Answer": "shorter",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "shorter",
        "Choice2": "shortest",
        "Choice3": "longer",
        "Choice4": "longest",
        "Question": "Very High Frequency (VHF) have __________ wavelengths?",
        "id": 430
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Convex",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "concave",
        "Choice2": "Convex",
        "Choice3": "diverging",
        "Choice4": "none of these",
        "Question": "Long-sight defect could be corrected by using __________ lens?",
        "id": 431
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Night blindness",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Night blindness",
        "Choice2": "rickets",
        "Choice3": "scurvy",
        "Choice4": "hair fall",
        "Question": "Deficiency of Vitamin-A results in __________?",
        "id": 432
    },
    {
        "Answer": "increase",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "also decrease",
        "Choice2": "increase",
        "Choice3": "remains constant",
        "Choice4": "none of these",
        "Question": "For a fixed mass of gass at constant temperature, if we decrease volume, the pressure will _________?",
        "id": 433
    },
    {
        "Answer": "120",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "60",
        "Choice2": "120",
        "Choice3": "180",
        "Choice4": "240",
        "Question": "The lifespan of Red Blood Cells is __________ days?",
        "id": 434
    },
    {
        "Answer": "1 g/cm3",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "1 g/cm3",
        "Choice2": "1.5 g/cm3",
        "Choice3": "2 g/cm3",
        "Choice4": "none of these",
        "Question": "The density of water is __________?",
        "id": 435
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Bacquerel",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Kelvin",
        "Choice2": "Thomson",
        "Choice3": "Rutherford",
        "Choice4": "Bacquerel",
        "Question": "Radioactivity was discovered by __________?",
        "id": 436
    },
    {
        "Answer": "battery",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "motor",
        "Choice2": "generator",
        "Choice3": "moving-coil meter",
        "Choice4": "battery",
        "Question": "A device which converts chemical energy into electrical energy is called __________?",
        "id": 437
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Star",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Star",
        "Choice2": "Planet",
        "Choice3": "Asteroid",
        "Choice4": "Meteor",
        "Question": "The Sun is a __________?",
        "id": 438
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ammonia",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Nitrogen",
        "Choice2": "Carbon dioxide",
        "Choice3": "Methane",
        "Choice4": "Ammonia",
        "Question": "The gas used in a refrigerator to cool water is___________?",
        "id": 439
    },
    {
        "Answer": "5",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "4",
        "Choice2": "5",
        "Choice3": "6",
        "Choice4": "7",
        "Question": "The average adult has a blood volume of about __________ liters.",
        "id": 440
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hydrogen",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Oxygen",
        "Choice2": "Hydrogen",
        "Choice3": "Carbon Dioxide",
        "Choice4": "Silicon",
        "Question": "The most abundant element in the universe is __________.",
        "id": 441
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Oxygen",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Oxygen",
        "Choice2": "Hydrogen",
        "Choice3": "Carbon Dioxide",
        "Choice4": "Silicon",
        "Question": "The most abundant element in the Earth’s crust is __________?",
        "id": 442
    },
    {
        "Answer": "15,000 to 20,000",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "5,000 to 10,000",
        "Choice2": "10,000 to 15,000",
        "Choice3": "15,000 to 20,000",
        "Choice4": "20,000 to 25,000",
        "Question": "Each day human body breathe in __________ liters of air.",
        "id": 443
    },
    {
        "Answer": "rickets",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "night blindness",
        "Choice2": "rickets",
        "Choice3": "scurvy",
        "Choice4": "hair fall",
        "Question": "Deficiency of Vitamin-D results in __________?",
        "id": 444
    },
    {
        "Answer": "pascal",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "pascal",
        "Choice2": "joule",
        "Choice3": "tesla",
        "Choice4": "henry",
        "Question": "The SI unit of “pressure” is _________.",
        "id": 445
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Osmium",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Platinum",
        "Choice2": "Copper",
        "Choice3": "Steel",
        "Choice4": "Osmium",
        "Question": "The most densest substance on the Earth is __________.",
        "id": 446
    },
    {
        "Answer": "convex lens",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "convex lens",
        "Choice2": "concave lens",
        "Choice3": "condenser lens",
        "Choice4": "none of these",
        "Question": "A camera uses a __________ to form an image.",
        "id": 447
    },
    {
        "Answer": "All are conductors",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Aluminium",
        "Choice2": "Gold",
        "Choice3": "Graphite",
        "Choice4": "All are conductors",
        "Question": "Which from the following is NOT a conductor?",
        "id": 448
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Compressed Natural Gas",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Converted Natural Gas",
        "Choice2": "Conduced Natural Gas",
        "Choice3": "onducted Natural Gas",
        "Choice4": "Compressed Natural Gas",
        "Question": "CNG stands for?",
        "id": 449
    },
    {
        "Answer": "7",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "5",
        "Choice2": " 6",
        "Choice3": "7",
        "Choice4": "8",
        "Question": "When white light is passed through a prism, it splits into __________ colours.",
        "id": 450
    },
    {
        "Answer": "10-9 meter",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "10-3 meter",
        "Choice2": "10-6 meter",
        "Choice3": "10-9 meter",
        "Choice4": "10-12 meter",
        "Question": "1 nanometer = ?",
        "id": 451
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Pyrometer",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Pyroscope",
        "Choice2": "Pyrometer",
        "Choice3": "Seismograph",
        "Choice4": "Xylometer",
        "Question": "Instrument used for measuring very high temperature is __________?",
        "id": 452
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Longitudinal",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Transverse",
        "Choice2": "Electromagnetic",
        "Choice3": "Longitudinal",
        "Choice4": "none of these",
        "Question": "Sound waves are _________ waves.",
        "id": 453
    },
    {
        "Answer": "5 – 21 days",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "1 – 5 days",
        "Choice2": "3 – 7 days",
        "Choice3": "4 – 8 days",
        "Choice4": "5 – 21 days",
        "Question": "The lifespan of White Blood Cells is __________ day(s)?",
        "id": 454
    },
    {
        "Answer": "plasma",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "plasma",
        "Choice2": "platelets",
        "Choice3": "blood cells",
        "Choice4": "None of these",
        "Question": "The fluid part of blood is known as __________?",
        "id": 455
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Salt",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Salt",
        "Choice2": "Chlorine",
        "Choice3": "Carbon dioxide",
        "Choice4": "Water",
        "Question": "During winter in cold countries, the __________ is mixed to melt the ice on the icy roads.",
        "id": 456
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sea water",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "River water",
        "Choice2": "Canal water",
        "Choice3": "Sea water",
        "Choice4": "Water in a lake",
        "Question": "In a very low temperature which from the following will freeze at last?",
        "id": 457
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Venus",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Venus",
        "Choice2": "Mercury",
        "Choice3": "Mars",
        "Choice4": "Moon",
        "Question": "The nearest planet to the Earth is _________?",
        "id": 458
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Mercury",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Jupiter",
        "Choice2": "Venus",
        "Choice3": "Mars",
        "Choice4": "Mercury",
        "Question": "The planet that moves round the Sun at the highest speed is_________?",
        "id": 459
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Highly elliptical",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Elliptical",
        "Choice2": "Highly elliptical",
        "Choice3": "Circular",
        "Choice4": "Parabolic",
        "Question": "In general, Comets have __________ orbits",
        "id": 460
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Global Positioning System",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Global Poles System",
        "Choice2": "Global PolySiliconium Store",
        "Choice3": "Global Positioning System",
        "Choice4": "Global Position Structure",
        "Question": "GPS is an abbreviation for?",
        "id": 461
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Loss of Electrons",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Gain of Electrons",
        "Choice2": "Loss of Electrons",
        "Choice3": "Gain of Protons",
        "Choice4": "Loss of Protons",
        "Question": "Oxidation is a chemical reaction involving the __________?",
        "id": 462
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Oxygen – Carbon dioxide",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Oxygen – Carbon dioxide",
        "Choice2": "Carbon dioxide – Oxygen",
        "Choice3": "Oxygen – Carbon monoxide",
        "Choice4": "Carbon monoxide – Oxygen",
        "Question": "At night, Plants intake __________ and release __________?",
        "id": 463
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Kidneys",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Kidneys",
        "Choice2": "Lungs",
        "Choice3": "Large intestine",
        "Choice4": "Liver",
        "Question": "Urine is produced in __________?",
        "id": 464
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Kidneys",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Lungs",
        "Choice2": "Liver",
        "Choice3": "Heart",
        "Choice4": "Kidneys",
        "Question": "Blood is cleaned by __________?",
        "id": 465
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Venus",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Mercury",
        "Choice2": "Venus",
        "Choice3": "Mars",
        "Choice4": "Jupiter",
        "Question": "The planet which is easily visible from the Earth is?",
        "id": 466
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jupiter",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Saturn",
        "Choice2": "Venus",
        "Choice3": "Mars",
        "Choice4": "Jupiter",
        "Question": "The Great Spot is on the planet __________?",
        "id": 467
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Jupiter",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Mars",
        "Choice2": "Saturn",
        "Choice3": "Uranus",
        "Choice4": "Jupiter",
        "Question": "The bodyguard of the Earth is __________ that save the Earth from many Comets and Asteroids.",
        "id": 468
    },
    {
        "Answer": "5",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "3",
        "Choice2": "4",
        "Choice3": "5",
        "Choice4": "6",
        "Question": "The planets visible to us without using a telescope are __________?",
        "id": 469
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Blood glucose level",
        "Categ": "EveryDay Science",
        "Choice1": "Blood glucose level",
        "Choice2": "The body pH value",
        "Choice3": "Amount of hemoglobin",
        "Choice4": "Salinity in Urine",
        "Question": "Biosensor is used to measure?",
        "id": 470
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Conceited",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Conceited",
        "Choice2": "Humble",
        "Choice3": "Progressive",
        "Choice4": "Noble",
        "Question": "Synonym of ARROGANT is _____________?",
        "id": 471
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Watchful",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Intelligent",
        "Choice2": "Energetic",
        "Choice3": "Observant",
        "Choice4": "Watchful",
        "Question": "Synonym of ALERT is _____________?",
        "id": 472
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Misappropriate",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Remunerate",
        "Choice2": "Clear",
        "Choice3": "Balance",
        "Choice4": "Misappropriate",
        "Question": "Synonym of EMBEZZLE is _____________?",
        "id": 473
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Short",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Small",
        "Choice2": "Short",
        "Choice3": "Little",
        "Choice4": "Limited",
        "Question": "Synonym of BRIEF is _____________?",
        "id": 474
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Abuse",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Abuse",
        "Choice2": "Appreciate",
        "Choice3": "Copy",
        "Choice4": "Encourage",
        "Question": "Synonym of Vituperate is _____________?",
        "id": 475
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Unreliable",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Dishonest",
        "Choice2": "Honest",
        "Choice3": "Reliable",
        "Choice4": "Unreliable",
        "Question": "Synonym of Incredulous is _____________?",
        "id": 476
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Puzzle",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Question",
        "Choice2": "Puzzle",
        "Choice3": "Answer",
        "Choice4": "Content",
        "Question": "Synonym of Enigma is _____________?",
        "id": 477
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cyclic",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Direct",
        "Choice2": "Strong",
        "Choice3": "Cyclic",
        "Choice4": "Weak",
        "Question": "Synonym of CIRCUITOUS is _____________?",
        "id": 478
    },
    {
        "Answer": "very thin",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "very fat",
        "Choice2": "very thin",
        "Choice3": "very small",
        "Choice4": "very heavy",
        "Question": "Synonym of EMACIATED is _____________?",
        "id": 479
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Laxity",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Serenity",
        "Choice2": "Laxity",
        "Choice3": "Active",
        "Choice4": "Bold",
        "Question": "Synonym of LETHARGY is _____________?",
        "id": 480
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Representative",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Representative",
        "Choice2": "Officer",
        "Choice3": "Member",
        "Choice4": "Servant",
        "Question": "Synonym of DELEGATE is _____________?",
        "id": 481
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Perilous",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Safe",
        "Choice2": "Brittle",
        "Choice3": "Perilous",
        "Choice4": "none of these",
        "Question": "Synonym of PRECARIOUS is _____________?",
        "id": 482
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Lie",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Truth",
        "Choice2": "Early",
        "Choice3": "Lie",
        "Choice4": "Delay",
        "Question": "Synonym of PREVARICATE is _____________?",
        "id": 483
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Ooze",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Ooze",
        "Choice2": "Overflow",
        "Choice3": "Wither",
        "Choice4": "Evaporate",
        "Question": "Synonym of EXUDE is _____________?",
        "id": 484
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Fanatic",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Fanatic",
        "Choice2": "Apathy",
        "Choice3": "Liberal",
        "Choice4": "Impious",
        "Question": "Synonym of ZEALOT is _____________?",
        "id": 485
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Enthusiasm",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Passive",
        "Choice2": "Enthusiasm",
        "Choice3": "Disgust",
        "Choice4": "Various",
        "Question": "Synonym of ZEST is _____________?",
        "id": 486
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Require",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Require",
        "Choice2": "Extra",
        "Choice3": "Unwanted",
        "Choice4": "Muted",
        "Question": "Synonym of YEARN is _____________?",
        "id": 487
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Shout",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Shackle",
        "Choice2": "Hitch",
        "Choice3": "Whisper",
        "Choice4": "Shout",
        "Question": "Synonym of YELL is _____________?",
        "id": 488
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Harness",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Detach",
        "Choice2": "Harness",
        "Choice3": "Release",
        "Choice4": "Liberate",
        "Question": "Synonym of YOKE is _____________?",
        "id": 489
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Heroism",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Stable",
        "Choice2": "Coward",
        "Choice3": "Heroism",
        "Choice4": "Fear",
        "Question": "Synonym of VALOUR is _____________?",
        "id": 490
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Roving",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Roving",
        "Choice2": "Stable",
        "Choice3": "Honoured",
        "Choice4": "Stubborn",
        "Question": "Synonym of VAGRANT is _____________?",
        "id": 491
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Prudent",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Heedless",
        "Choice2": "Prudent",
        "Choice3": "Reckless",
        "Choice4": "Negligent",
        "Question": "Synonym of WARY is _____________?",
        "id": 492
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Decline",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Employ",
        "Choice2": "Decline",
        "Choice3": "Rise",
        "Choice4": "Revive",
        "Question": "Synonym of WANE _____________?",
        "id": 493
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Exert",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Abstain",
        "Choice2": "Avoid",
        "Choice3": "Forgo",
        "Choice4": "Exert",
        "Question": "Synonym of WIELD _____________?",
        "id": 494
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Destruction",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Built",
        "Choice2": "Implement",
        "Choice3": "Destruction",
        "Choice4": "Fresh",
        "Question": "The synonyms of Catastrophe is__________?",
        "id": 495
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Scorn",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "love",
        "Choice2": "Scorn",
        "Choice3": "Accept",
        "Choice4": "Luddite",
        "Question": "The Synonyms of Disdain is_____________?",
        "id": 496
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Stubborn",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Agree",
        "Choice2": "Scorn",
        "Choice3": "Stubborn",
        "Choice4": "Soft",
        "Question": "The Synonyms of OBSTINATE is____________?",
        "id": 497
    },
    {
        "Answer": "A confused mixture",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Fear of strangers",
        "Choice2": "A confused mixture",
        "Choice3": "Free of cost",
        "Choice4": "Synopsis",
        "Question": "The Synonym of Farrago is_____________?",
        "id": 498
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Unprincipled politician",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Unprincipled politician",
        "Choice2": "Sneak",
        "Choice3": "Garrulous",
        "Choice4": "None of above",
        "Question": "The Synonym of ‘snollygoster’ is_________?",
        "id": 499
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Accept",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Accept",
        "Choice2": "Acceptable",
        "Choice3": "Condomn",
        "Choice4": "Condemn",
        "Question": "The Synonyms of CONDONE is__________?",
        "id": 500
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Immature",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Mature",
        "Choice2": "Immature",
        "Choice3": "purity",
        "Choice4": "power",
        "Question": "The Synonym of Puerile is______________?",
        "id": 501
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Diminish",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Postpone",
        "Choice2": "Abandon",
        "Choice3": "Diminish",
        "Choice4": "Increase",
        "Question": "Synonym of ABATE is _____________?",
        "id": 502
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Pleasant",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Unpleasant",
        "Choice2": "Pleasant",
        "Choice3": "Heart",
        "Choice4": "Love",
        "Question": "Synonym of Cordial is _____________?",
        "id": 503
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Flattery",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Flattery",
        "Choice2": "Embezzle",
        "Choice3": "Knowledge",
        "Choice4": "Satiate",
        "Question": "Synonym of Cajole is _____________?",
        "id": 504
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Victory",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Victory",
        "Choice2": "Victim",
        "Choice3": "Violence",
        "Choice4": "Its Name of US President",
        "Question": "Synonym of Triumph is _____________?",
        "id": 505
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Airtight",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Airtight",
        "Choice2": "Imitate",
        "Choice3": "Unsettled",
        "Choice4": "Open",
        "Question": "Synonym of Hermetic is _____________?",
        "id": 506
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Fake",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Fake",
        "Choice2": "Deplorable",
        "Choice3": "Purse",
        "Choice4": "Robust",
        "Question": "Synonym of SHAM",
        "id": 507
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cautiously",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Cautiously",
        "Choice2": "Retrospectively",
        "Choice3": "Hectically",
        "Choice4": "Carelessly",
        "Question": "Synonym of GINGERLY",
        "id": 508
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Tame",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Tame",
        "Choice2": "Stingy",
        "Choice3": "Jab",
        "Choice4": "Frail",
        "Question": "Synonym of MEEK",
        "id": 509
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Bony",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Weighty",
        "Choice2": "Bony",
        "Choice3": "Fatty",
        "Choice4": "Big statement",
        "Question": "Synonym of GAUNT",
        "id": 510
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Minor role",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Funny character",
        "Choice2": "Minor role",
        "Choice3": "Type of Fiction",
        "Choice4": "Sharp tool",
        "Question": "Synonyms of CAMEO",
        "id": 511
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Commonplace",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Minor",
        "Choice2": "Sad",
        "Choice3": "Commonplace",
        "Choice4": "Swindler",
        "Question": "Synonym of TRITE_____________?",
        "id": 512
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Tasty",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Tasty",
        "Choice2": "Old",
        "Choice3": "Filthy",
        "Choice4": "Bumpy",
        "Question": "Synonym of Scrumptious _____________?",
        "id": 513
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Affability",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Affability",
        "Choice2": "Big",
        "Choice3": "Turbulent",
        "Choice4": "Grope",
        "Question": "Synonym of Bonhomie______________?",
        "id": 514
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cajole",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Fast",
        "Choice2": "Cajole",
        "Choice3": "Waive",
        "Choice4": "Slander",
        "Question": "Synonym of Wheedle ___________________?",
        "id": 515
    },
    {
        "Answer": "To Prolong",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "To Promote",
        "Choice2": "To Prolong",
        "Choice3": "To proactive",
        "Choice4": "To Provide",
        "Question": "Synonym of Prolix______________?",
        "id": 516
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Clever",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Clever",
        "Choice2": "thin",
        "Choice3": "Fast",
        "Choice4": "Slow",
        "Question": "Synonym of Canny_____________?",
        "id": 517
    },
    {
        "Answer": "To chase",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "To chase",
        "Choice2": "To fix",
        "Choice3": "To divert",
        "Choice4": "To disturb",
        "Question": "Synonym of Trail_________?",
        "id": 518
    },
    {
        "Answer": "postpone",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "cancel",
        "Choice2": "discuss",
        "Choice3": "reconsider",
        "Choice4": "postpone",
        "Question": "Synonym of Shelve_____________________?",
        "id": 519
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hand to hand",
        "Categ": "Synonyms",
        "Choice1": "Hand to hand",
        "Choice2": "Street to street",
        "Choice3": "District to district",
        "Choice4": "City to city",
        "Question": "Synonym of “Mano a Mano”",
        "id": 520
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Condense",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Congest",
        "Choice2": "Conclude",
        "Choice3": "Convert",
        "Choice4": "Condense",
        "Question": "Antonym of EXPAND is _____________?",
        "id": 521
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Natural",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Red",
        "Choice2": "Solid",
        "Choice3": "Truthful",
        "Choice4": "Natural",
        "Question": "Antonym of ARTIFICIAL is ______________?",
        "id": 522
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Tiny",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Fragile",
        "Choice2": "Weak",
        "Choice3": "Tiny",
        "Choice4": "Soft",
        "Question": "Antonym of ENORMOUS is_____________?",
        "id": 523
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Manifest",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Hermetic",
        "Choice2": "Manifest",
        "Choice3": "Pedantic",
        "Choice4": "Occult",
        "Question": "Antonym of RECONDITE is_____________?",
        "id": 524
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Apathy",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Apathy",
        "Choice2": "Nerve",
        "Choice3": "Initiative",
        "Choice4": "Sagacity",
        "Question": "Antonym of GUMPTION is _____________?",
        "id": 525
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Joy",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Hurt",
        "Choice2": "Irk",
        "Choice3": "Joy",
        "Choice4": "Huff",
        "Question": "Antonym of PIQUE is _____________?",
        "id": 526
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Homespun",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Homespun",
        "Choice2": "Cheerful",
        "Choice3": "Inelegant",
        "Choice4": "Sincere",
        "Question": "Antonym of SARTORIAL is _____________?",
        "id": 527
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Unyielding",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Pliable",
        "Choice2": "Pliant",
        "Choice3": "Quiet",
        "Choice4": "Unyielding",
        "Question": "Antonym of DOCILE is _____________?",
        "id": 528
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Inexpert",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Inexpert",
        "Choice2": "Acute",
        "Choice3": "Active",
        "Choice4": "Able",
        "Question": "Antonym of DEXTEROUS is _____________?",
        "id": 529
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Prolong",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Cramp",
        "Choice2": "Prolong",
        "Choice3": "Chop",
        "Choice4": "Clip",
        "Question": "Antonym of CURTAIL is _____________?",
        "id": 530
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Regular",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Bent",
        "Choice2": "Devious",
        "Choice3": "Regular",
        "Choice4": "Atypical",
        "Question": "Antonym of DEVIANT is _____________?",
        "id": 531
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Stiff",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Docile",
        "Choice2": "Pliable",
        "Choice3": "Stiff",
        "Choice4": "Supple",
        "Question": "Antonym of DUCTILE is _____________?",
        "id": 532
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Wise",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Trivial",
        "Choice2": "Silly",
        "Choice3": "Petty",
        "Choice4": "Wise",
        "Question": "Antonym of FRIVOLOUS is _____________?",
        "id": 533
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Attach",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Attach",
        "Choice2": "Detach",
        "Choice3": "Discourage",
        "Choice4": "Halt",
        "Question": "Antonym of WEAN is _____________?",
        "id": 534
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Thrifty",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Spendthrift",
        "Choice2": "Squandering",
        "Choice3": "Thrifty",
        "Choice4": "Wanton",
        "Question": "Antonym of PRODIGAL is _____________?",
        "id": 535
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Apparent",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Misty",
        "Choice2": "Apparent",
        "Choice3": "Murky",
        "Choice4": "Shadowy",
        "Question": "Antonym of NEBULOUS is _____________?",
        "id": 536
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Whole",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Bit",
        "Choice2": "Bug",
        "Choice3": "Insect",
        "Choice4": "Whole",
        "Question": "Antonym of MITE is _____________?",
        "id": 537
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Dictated",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Punish",
        "Choice2": "Dictated",
        "Choice3": "Grand",
        "Choice4": "Small",
        "Question": "Antonym of TACIT is _____________?",
        "id": 538
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Vivacious",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Vivacious",
        "Choice2": "Witty",
        "Choice3": "Empty",
        "Choice4": "Full",
        "Question": "Antonym of DOLEFUL is _____________?",
        "id": 539
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Generosity",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Verbosity",
        "Choice2": "Generosity",
        "Choice3": "Clan",
        "Choice4": "Tenderness",
        "Question": "Antonym of PARSIMONY is _____________?",
        "id": 540
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Truthful",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Credit",
        "Choice2": "Clean",
        "Choice3": "Truthful",
        "Choice4": "Dishonest",
        "Question": "Antonym of FALLACIOUS is _____________?",
        "id": 541
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Unimportant",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Unimportant",
        "Choice2": "Hindmost",
        "Choice3": "Disposed",
        "Choice4": "Mature",
        "Question": "Antonym of FOREMOST is _____________?",
        "id": 542
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Active",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Asleep",
        "Choice2": "Active",
        "Choice3": "Deactivated",
        "Choice4": "Fallow",
        "Question": "Antonym of QUIESCENT is _____________?",
        "id": 543
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cultured",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Smutty",
        "Choice2": "Uncultured",
        "Choice3": "Uncultured",
        "Choice4": "Cultured",
        "Question": "Antonym of PHILISTINE is _____________?",
        "id": 544
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Generous",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Generous",
        "Choice2": "Chintzy",
        "Choice3": "Closefisted",
        "Choice4": "Skimpy",
        "Question": "Antonym of NIGGARDLY is _____________?",
        "id": 545
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Unscramble",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Slant",
        "Choice2": "Unscramble",
        "Choice3": "Obscure",
        "Choice4": "Pervert",
        "Question": "Antonym of GARBLED is _____________?",
        "id": 546
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Alert",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Doting",
        "Choice2": "Anile",
        "Choice3": "Alert",
        "Choice4": "Ancient",
        "Question": "Antonym of SENILE is _____________?",
        "id": 547
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Moderate",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Dizzying",
        "Choice2": "Wasteful",
        "Choice3": "Wanton",
        "Choice4": "Moderate",
        "Question": "Antonym of INORDINATE is _____________?",
        "id": 548
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Vague",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Evident",
        "Choice2": "Obvious",
        "Choice3": "Explicit",
        "Choice4": "Vague",
        "Question": "Antonym of LUCID is _____________?",
        "id": 549
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Disgorge",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Disgorge",
        "Choice2": "Disrupt",
        "Choice3": "Absorb",
        "Choice4": "Devour",
        "Question": "Antonym of INGEST is _____________?",
        "id": 550
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Sad",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Roused",
        "Choice2": "Blissful",
        "Choice3": "Sad",
        "Choice4": "Happy",
        "Question": "Antonym of ELATED is _____________?",
        "id": 551
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Boost",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Asperse",
        "Choice2": "Besmirch",
        "Choice3": "Boost",
        "Choice4": "Vilify",
        "Question": "Antonym of DENIGRATE is _____________?",
        "id": 552
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Fresh",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Old",
        "Choice2": "Fresh",
        "Choice3": "Tale",
        "Choice4": "Break",
        "Question": "The antonyms of Stale is____________?",
        "id": 553
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Small",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Big",
        "Choice2": "Giant",
        "Choice3": "Small",
        "Choice4": "Low",
        "Question": "The antonym of Mammoth is___________?",
        "id": 554
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Rigid",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Yielding",
        "Choice2": "Rigid",
        "Choice3": "Mold-able",
        "Choice4": "Supple",
        "Question": "Antonym of Elastic is _____________?",
        "id": 555
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Hostile",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Peacful",
        "Choice2": "Hostile",
        "Choice3": "Dominant",
        "Choice4": "Tuneful",
        "Question": "Antonym of Harmonious is _____________?",
        "id": 556
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Serious",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Teasing",
        "Choice2": "Serious",
        "Choice3": "Tongue-in-check",
        "Choice4": "Copy",
        "Question": "Antonym of Facetious is _____________?",
        "id": 557
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Thrifty",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Wildly extravagant",
        "Choice2": "Dissolute",
        "Choice3": "Dissipated",
        "Choice4": "Thrifty",
        "Question": "“Profligate” Antonym _________?",
        "id": 558
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Depredation",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Lexicon",
        "Choice2": "Balm",
        "Choice3": "Hoarding",
        "Choice4": "Depredation",
        "Question": "What is antonyms of word Restoration?",
        "id": 559
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Decent",
        "Categ": "Antonyms",
        "Choice1": "Abusive",
        "Choice2": "Ribald",
        "Choice3": "Decent",
        "Choice4": "Mitigate",
        "Question": "Antonym of SCURRILOUS is_____________?",
        "id": 560
    }
]
